<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-01-06T23:15:28+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Tomb Kings Chariots</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/showcase/2024/01/06/chariots.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tomb Kings Chariots" /><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/showcase/2024/01/06/chariots</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/showcase/2024/01/06/chariots.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/generated/images/2024-01-06-chariots/all-800-5c718f110.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2024-01-06-chariots/all-600-5c718f110.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2024-01-06-chariots/all-800-5c718f110.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2024-01-06-chariots/all-1000-5c718f110.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually finished these guys over the pandemic, but given that was before I set this site up, and with the re-release of Tomb Kings as a part of the old world, I though now would be a great time to show them off!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just a breif post as I’m really proud of this very simple conversion and with the release of The Old World, I hope it might show some people that are worried about the old minis that they don’t have to look old!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row; margin:0;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2024-01-06-chariots/standard-800-4500139c1.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2024-01-06-chariots/standard-600-4500139c1.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2024-01-06-chariots/standard-800-4500139c1.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2024-01-06-chariots/standard-1000-4500139c1.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2024-01-06-chariots/musician-800-2bcd4b4dc.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2024-01-06-chariots/musician-600-2bcd4b4dc.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2024-01-06-chariots/musician-800-2bcd4b4dc.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2024-01-06-chariots/musician-1000-2bcd4b4dc.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row; margin:0;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2024-01-06-chariots/champ1-800-747591a9e.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2024-01-06-chariots/champ1-600-747591a9e.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2024-01-06-chariots/champ1-800-747591a9e.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2024-01-06-chariots/champ1-1000-747591a9e.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2024-01-06-chariots/champ2-800-9eb4d586c.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2024-01-06-chariots/champ2-600-9eb4d586c.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2024-01-06-chariots/champ2-800-9eb4d586c.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2024-01-06-chariots/champ2-1000-9eb4d586c.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-conversions&quot;&gt;The Conversions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the Tomb Kings core models are probably as old as me, and lets face it, they look it. However, loads of the modern Tomb Kings kits come with plenty of spare parts that make updating the chariots a doddle. As you might be able to see all of the heads have been swapped out for spare Tomb Guard heads. On the unit champion I have also used the champion head from the Necropolis knights so that they don’t look identical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The musician is also the Tomb Guard musician arm. This is also just more practical than the actual musician because there is not much space for both the riders to fit, and the horn pointing outwards rather than wrapping around just gives a bit more space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also painted up a couple more that make use of the spare hooks from the Necropolis Knight riders, and I have used one of the spears as an additional weapon for one of the unit champions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;painting&quot;&gt;Painting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These guys were largely based on the scheme from the last version of the How To Paint Citadel Miniatures book that came out nearly 10 years ago (the one with the DVD). It was a good starting point but I wanted a bit more colour to it so opted for green as the primary and purple as the secondary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bone&quot;&gt;Bone&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Base: Zandri Dust&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All over wash: Seraphim Sepia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drybrush: Terminatus Stone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drybrush Praxetti White (or any normal white)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As there is a lot of dry brushing on these guys, I would suggest varnishing after doing all the non-metallic colours. Drybrushing can get dusty and rub off the miniatures over time more than normal painting, and a layer of varnish will just keep everything in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;green&quot;&gt;Green&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Base: Warpstone Glow&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recess Shape: Caliban green or Coelia Greenshade&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highlight: 50:50 Warpstone Glow &amp;amp; Moot Green&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highlight: Moot Green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warpstone glow has terrible coverage. Unfortunately I started these guys long before contrast paints existed. However, to speed up the painting process, since I normally spray the whole mini in zandri dust first, I then contrast warp lightning over the green areas and then layer Warpstone Glow until I get a solid coverage. If I could start this army again I would use a slightly more saturated green I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;purple&quot;&gt;Purple&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Base: Naggaroth Night&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recess Shade: Druchii Violet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highlight: Xereus Purple&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highlight: Genestealer Purple&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cream-fabrics&quot;&gt;Cream fabrics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Base: Zandri Dust&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wash: Agrax Earthshade&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Layer: Ushabti Bone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highlight; Screaming Skull&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highlight: White&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gold&quot;&gt;Gold&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Base: Retibutor Armour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recess shade: Seraphim Sepia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hightlight: Liberator Armour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bandages&quot;&gt;Bandages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Base: Rhinox Hide&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Layer: Gorthor Brown&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wash: Agrax Earthshade&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highlight: Gorthor Brown&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highlight: Baneblade Brown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>ollie</name></author><category term="Showcase" /><summary type="html">I actually finished these guys over the pandemic, but given that was before I set this site up, and with the re-release of Tomb Kings as a part of the old world, I though now would be a great time to show them off!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Golden Demon ‘23 Necron Doom Scythe</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/showcase/2023/07/20/golden-demon.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Golden Demon ‘23 Necron Doom Scythe" /><published>2023-07-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-07-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/showcase/2023/07/20/golden-demon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/showcase/2023/07/20/golden-demon.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/banner-800-2186545c0.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/banner-600-2186545c0.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/banner-800-2186545c0.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/banner-1000-2186545c0.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we are, my first Golden Demon entry in 10 years, and my first in the main competition. A lot has changed in that time – Large Scale has vanished, Small Scale has been added, and even all the trophies have had a re-design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had originally tried to get tickets for the Nottingham event at the end of 2022, but like most people, was unable to. That being said, it ended up working out for the best since I realised I had very little time to actually get an entry together back in 2022. In this article, I am going to go through the process that led me to get the final entry you see above with the concepts for my original ideas and then finally the feedback that I got from some great artists when I was chatting to them at Warhammer Fest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-category&quot;&gt;The Category&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew I was going to be busy in January, and I also had exams coming up in March, so I wanted to paint something small. I don’t think I’m quite there yet for the single miniature categories but I really enjoy doing weathering on vehicles and armour. The Small Scale category was ideal as I could make a scene that is relatively small and still play around with a lot of technical effects without having to worry about reposing or converting – at the end of the day a vehicle is a vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-concept&quot;&gt;The Concept&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hadn’t seen much diversity in the Small Scale category, in particular, I hadn’t seen any Necron flyers entered. I really liked the Doom Scythe anyway as it has plenty of hard edges that make lighting straightforward, as well as plenty of sources that can be used for OSL so I knew that was the mini I wanted to go for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that I also wanted to avoid was a backdrop. Firstly, I saw them on most flying entries as a way to set the scene, but since a lot of the sources of glowing light on the Doom Scythe are from underneath, I didn’t want to hide it with a board behind the model. Secondly, I have never tried to do 2D painting like that before, and I did not have the time to experiment. Instead, I needed to find a way to have the Doom Scythe close to something in order to pin it in a flying position without it seeming forced – I needed a good story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now full disclosure, I didn’t end up doing this so feel free to skip ahead a bit, but if you are interested in what I was originally trying to do and my initial experiments, then read on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been floating a lot of ideas on this for a while, some of which shifted around and I may revisit at a later date. I loved the idea of seeing the planes come in to land, so wanted to do the Doom Scythe flying back into the tomb, perhaps through a canyon wall that on one side simply looks like a cave entrance and on the other is this vast open space with some blue lighting coming from deep within. The Doom Scythe could be flying sideways to get through the crack in the wall and thus I could attach it there. Still, that’s potentially obscuring a lot of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stalagmites? Yeah, that makes sense – the tomb world has been there for billions of years, near the edges it is likely there will be rock formations which may not have been cleared yet. At one end we have the tomb world at the other there is a transition into a rocky cave. The Doom Scythe can be weaving through, and the stalagmites will provide a great way to cast some more shadows around the cave. Great there we have it, so how do I make it look like a tomb world?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-first-attempt-at-a-base&quot;&gt;The First Attempt at a Base&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img caption=&quot;Two bases I had a go at sculpting milliput rocks on&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/rocks-800-b819825d1.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/rocks-600-b819825d1.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/rocks-800-b819825d1.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/rocks-1000-b819825d1.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I played around with a lot of ideas but effectively I needed to cut up and tile the floor in geometric shapes, much like the ones we see on Necron vehicles like the Monolith. First I tried rolling out a big sheet of Milliput and tried to see if I could carve and break that up how I wanted. I struggled to get it quite thin enough, and my carving looked far too irregular. While to a certain extent there would be some irregularities, at the Small Scale it wouldn’t be so apparent and so I decided that wasn’t going to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up I tried cutting up some plasticard. This worked better, and in fact, I realised I could turn some of the offcuts into small crystals that worked quite well. However, it was tricky to get the distance between the tiles sorted such that it was clean but not too large. Nonetheless, I also used this as an opportunity to practice my sculpting and put some rocks and stalagmites on there to see how they would turn out. I had an image of Albert Moreto Font’s Nottingham 2022 entry next to me since I liked how the rocks turned out on that and I had also seen a lot of WIPs on Instagram of it so I tried to recreate some of those shapes. My only concern was the stalagmites were a bit difficult to make sufficiently tall. I knew that I would have a pin through them anyway, but for the scale, I think they may have looked a bit off. Anyway, I knew I could at least sculpt something more if I needed to. So back to sorting the Tomb World floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, what better way to make something look like it was made by machines than… well… making it with a machine? I jumped on Adobe Illustrator and drew out some designs. This was actually ideal as I could also etch some Necron glyphs into the floors. It was coming to the end of March at this point so I had 1 month to get everything sorted. No fear though, I had a week off work to do exactly that, so my flatmate kindly agreed to laser cut the pieces for me and I could get everything built and start painting straight away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slight snag… I got them cut 2/3 the size they should have been and we wouldn’t get a chance to get some new ones cut for another week. So I couldn’t finish the base now and I’d have to make use of my time off differently. It’s fine though – I’ll have plenty of time to come back to this later right? I did use some of the time to at least mock up a smaller scale (of a small scale entry) to check the rocks looked right on the design and get some colours down. I still wasn’t happy with the stalagmites though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;test-schemes&quot;&gt;Test Schemes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/Test1-800-598a1f690.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/Test1-600-598a1f690.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/Test1-800-598a1f690.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/Test1-1000-598a1f690.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/Test2-800-113930673.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/Test2-600-113930673.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/Test2-800-113930673.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/Test2-1000-113930673.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, so the base was on pause for now, but the mini is of course the most important part of your entry, the base is just the frame for it, so I should get that sorted first. I had been inspired by a lot of Votann colour schemes that use a dirty cream off-white with orange and blue/black spot colours and wanted to try and recreate that. I had also seen Richard Grey’s technique for how he paints his Imperial fists and figured that the stippling scheme would help (a) build up the colours gradually so I get a smooth gradient from fairly dark to bright and (b) help me control where the lighting is coming from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, the Aeronautica Doom Scythe squadron comes with two of the flyers, so I used the one that was slightly damaged (annoyingly it arrived with a small part snapped off) to try out the colours before jumping onto the proper one. Not least because this was a lot of OSL, which I hadn’t had the chance to do on such a large area before. Before painting, I dinged up the hull with a Dremel to make it look like it had taken some dents over the years. I felt this would add a bit more visual interest as well as help me signpost where the light was coming from a bit more since the panels were largely flat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To a certain extent, the stippling worked. However, it was still a bit too brown so ended up going in with an airbrush to brighten things up a bit. Now it just looked a bit too…. Fleshy… and the orange wouldn’t pop quite how I liked it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went through a couple more iterations, including one where I just stripped the whole model and tried to light it entirely from the glow of the weapons underneath which, while cool, did not leave much more to be done to really wow the GD judges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I decided to just paint it white with a neutral brown shading. Fab now I can &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; start on the entry itself… I have 3 weeks to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-mini&quot;&gt;The mini&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay so starting with an airbrush, I primed black and then added a directional lighting of white ink coming from a harsh angle from the side. I then proceeded to airbrush the darker areas Celestra Grey, and the lighter areas Ulthuan Grey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add a bit more modulation in tone on the light and dark side, I airbrushed a very thin glaze along the centre of the panels on the dark side Stormvermin Fur, and highlighted the edges of the light side with white ink through the airbrush. Block in the central cockpit area black, and the metallics with Iron Hands steel and great we are off to the races.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;refining-the-white&quot;&gt;Refining the White&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paints used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stormvermin Fur&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celestra Grey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ulthuam Grey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;White Scar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shade the recesses across the white areas (both light and dark) with pure Stormvermin fur. For the dark side I made a 50:50 mix of Celestra and Stormvermin, pure Celestra and a 50:50 mix of Celestra and Ulthuan, for the light side it was Ulthuan, 50:50 Ulthuan and White, and then White.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I intentionally made sure that the airbrush didn’t cover in a single out-of-the-pot colour I had to iterate between the different mixes for each half to highlight it up, I only used the darkest of each (i.e. 50:50 Celstra and Stormvermin for dark side and Ulthuan for light side)in a couple of places just to smooth out some of the transitions. I highlighted all the edges facing the light source and glazed towards those edges to give a smooth transition. I also put lots of small scratches across the hull in all but the lightest colours on each half so that it adds a cool weathered texture without looking explicitly like fresh battle damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;black-cockpit&quot;&gt;Black Cockpit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paints used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Abbadon black&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Incubi Darkness&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dark Reaper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thunderhawk Blue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Russ Grey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fenrisian Grey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flat black is quite a harsh colour and so I wanted to soften that ever so slightly. With an Artis Opus drybrush I stippled some Incubi Darkness across the area, focussing on the edges to add a bit more variation to this panel – make sure to mask off the white areas though to avoid any overbrushing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then highlighted starting from Dark Reaper and through Thunderhawk Blue, Russ grey and Fenrisian Grey, again largely focusing edges on the lightest side. I also glazed up some of the Thunderhawk blue on the surfaces that were directly perpendicular to the light. On the further side of the cockpit, I only went up to Russ Grey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;blue-osl&quot;&gt;Blue OSL&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paints used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ahriman Blue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Temple Guard Blue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bahroth Blue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact I hadn’t finished all the details, it was at this point that for some reason I decided to do the OSL. Which was dumb, but fortunately it worked out. I had watched plenty of videos online but it was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6X3nfKwaFRI&amp;amp;ab_channel=ZumikitoMiniatures&quot;&gt;Zumikito’s video&lt;/a&gt; that finally made it stick. I was mainly concerned about how to make the glow blue but not wash out the fact there was also environmental lighting coming from the side. Turns out since I was already using white anyway, it was just a matter of glazing Bahroth Blue down the hull and the results worked perfectly, it’s actually my favourite bit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an aside, when I had originally tried this on my test model I had tried glazing dark blues first. In hindsight, this clearly doesn’t make sense which is why it looks so weird (unfortunately I don’t have many pictures). The reason it doesn’t work, is the weapons are a light source. Regardless of what environmental lighting there is, the weapons shouldn’t make anything darker. Therefore using any colour which has a darker value than that which you are covering will look weird – Bahroth blue has a slightly higher value than Celestra grey and so adds to the lighting which is why it works so well. This is a particular learning point I’m definitely going to take on in future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;orang-rings&quot;&gt;Orang Rings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paints used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wild Rider red&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Troll Slayer orange&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fire Dragon Bright&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stormvermin Fur&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start I mentioned how I wanted orange in there too, so better find a way to put that on! I really liked the Novokh dynasty studio doom scythe which had some of the Necron glyphs over the top in white, and figured some similar freehand would work just as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stuck a load of layers of masking tape together and cut out various-sized circles from it to make a template that I put over the mini. I sprayed from the darker side Wild Rider red and from the lighter side Troll Slayer orange. I then came back in with Wild Rider red to reinforce the darker side, reinforced the recesses again with Stormvermin Fur and then highlighted through Troll Slayer orange, Fire Dragon Bright and Kindle Flame in a similar manner as I did for the white.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I was overthinking (which I don’t think is possible for a GB entry) but I chose the specific layout of the circles to form a triangle that was pointing upwards towards the light. I was hoping this would then draw the eye away from the base and focus on what is important, namely the mini!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To weather the orange I then added some chips in Ulthuan and Celestra grey where appropriate to make it look like the paint had been scratched off in places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was worried since I had already done some OSL I would have to go back over it, but actually the original OSL was subtle enough where the orange was that it looked fine and didn’t disrupt the visuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;metallics&quot;&gt;Metallics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paints used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Iron Hands Steel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nuln oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Runefang Steel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relatively straightforward – Iron Hands Steel base, wash nuln oil, highlight Iron Hands Steel and then a bright silver. Since the metallic details were so small there was only really so much that could be done with this and time was ticking away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-weapons-and-the-pilot-glow&quot;&gt;The Weapons and the pilot glow&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paints used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ahriman Blue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Temple Guard Blue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bahroth Blue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;White Scar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was perhaps the trickiest bit, and I’m still not satisfied with the final results. I figured, because the parts were so small there was no chance I was going to be able to use an airbrush to make this look good. So I went in with some white ink over the areas that would hit the light and tried to glaze in Bahroth blue again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this was straight over metallics it seemed a bit abrupt. I tinkered around for ages to see if I could smooth it out but to no avail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, on the cockpit, I wanted to really make this a point of focus so wanted blue environmental lighting around the pilot in the middle of the black panel. Since the light was theoretically coming from below I tried to do the same thing but the top surfaces were kept metal. Again it didn’t have the effect I wanted. I got back out the test mini to see whether I could, in fact, airbrush the glow to at least try and tidy it up a bit, and it did actually work better than I thought (though still not perfect).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in the end I went over all the glowing parts with Ahriman Blue, Temple Guard Blue and Bahroth Blue. I then painted the deepest parts of any of the light sources with white just to make it look particularly hot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also put a bit of varnish on the sources to help amplify this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I did the orange glowing parts as spot colours using the same paints as the orange rings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right so mini finally finished, I just have a week and a half to sort the whole base right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-base-i-went-with&quot;&gt;The Base I went with&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The base was on my mind constantly during those last couple of weeks because it was starting to dawn on me that it might be a bit ambitious, and I would need a lot of practice first to get it to turn out how I wanted. I had been thinking about other ideas that I could have some wreckage that it was flying by but was worried about ruining the sense of scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, I had considered some of the curved armour parts from some of the Necron vehicle kits – cut up correctly they can be non-descript Necron ruins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, when I should have been working, I had a eureka moment. Lying in my cupboard for nearly 10 years has been an Eldar Wave Serpent. It had previously been my brother’s when he had briefly done Warhammer and had been given to me when he lost interest. I had been planning to use it for a base on my Necron Tomb Stalker, which has also been sitting unbuilt for nearly 10 years…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the front fins on the armour of that were ideal since they could be mounted to look like part of a webway portal. I hacked off the appropriate bits with a saw and stripped them. I also tried to remove as much of the glue as I could but I couldn’t get all of it, so the construction was not as clean as I would have liked. Some of it I was able to just cover up with dirt anyway so not the end of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stuck it to a plinth and went for a creamy bone colour which ended up turning out horrendously. Fortunately, I had the other fin that I was using to test schemes on, and realised that red looked much better. I was initially hesitant of using too much colour on the base since I did not want it to draw attention from the model itself, but since the red sort of went with the orange, I felt that this worked okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img caption=&quot;Initial test scheme for the base&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/cream_base-800-0341a87d7.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/cream_base-600-0341a87d7.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/cream_base-800-0341a87d7.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/cream_base-1000-0341a87d7.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I stripped the main fin and committed to adding dirt and rocks around it. The rocks were made up of bark and medium slate that I had found in the park. The sizes I found were actually the perfect size to surround the hole base without too much gap filling so it really looks like it bursts out of the ground. The ground is actual dirt, stuck on with PVA glue and then crumbled on top. I made sure to stick the bark and dirt in the oven for an hour to kill anything before sticking it on. I also drilled a hole in the top of the three prongs to later mount the mini.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m actually really happy with the composition of the base and think it actually ended up miles better than what I had originally planned. It really is true that sometimes simpler is just better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;painting-the-red&quot;&gt;Painting the red&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paints used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Khorne red&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mephiston red&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evil Suns Scarlet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wild Rider red&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Troll Slayer orange&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fire Dragon Bright&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Incubi Darkness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole base was primed in black and then a burst of white ink was shot from where the light was coming from so that I could see where the highlights should be. I then came in with the Khorne red in the darker areas and Mephiston red in the lighter areas. I was really worried about making the base too bright and it drawing attention away so I didn’t do too many layers of Khorne red to really keep the colour dull. I then came in along the brightest edges in Evil Suns Scarlett down one side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I started glazing these three colours into their respective areas to start to build up the highlights and shadows. In particular, I came in with scratches of the mid-tones to add a bit of texture. For example, since I had not done a solid coat of any of the colours, going over it with the same colour on a normal brush does slightly highlight the colour. So tiny scratches of Khorne red over the dark areas. I also shaded the recesses with a mix of Incubi Darkness and Khorne red .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then highlighted through the rest of the colours largely focussing on the edges and getting finer and finer. Fire Dragon Bright was only used as a dot highlight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A particular thing to bear in mind is that the finish of paints when airbrushed vs normally brushed can be slightly different. Normally an airbrush tends to make things more matte. However, I knew I would be coming over it with varnish later anyway so it would homogenise the look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;painting-the-black&quot;&gt;Painting the black&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paints used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Abaddon black&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Corvus black&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eshin grey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dawnstone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Administratum grey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rhinox Hide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I liked the red, there wasn’t much visual interest on the fin so I decided to add two black stripes similar to how they are done on Saim-Hann Wave Serpents. I specifically angled these such that they pointed towards where the Doom Scythe would be mounted. I masked off two strips in the red panel and sprayed from Abaddon black to Eshin grey in a similar manner as I did for the red.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the back, I did some chunky highlights of the same colours and also glazed them into the bits that curved towards the light. I then edge highlighted with Dawnstone and Administratum grey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the recesses on the back, I also glazed in some Rhinox Hide to show the build-up of dirt and a bit of weathering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also didn’t want to add an additional colour to the base and make it look too busy, so I opted to make the gems black also and highlighted them up in an opaque manner i.e. with the highlights on the top right and no secondary reflection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stripes were then chipped with some red scratches to make it look like it was showing the paint underneath, in the same way, that I did with the orange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this, I gave it all a blast with gloss varnish to apply some transfer. A particular shout out to my friend Aiden who express shipped them to me with 3 days to go so I could put them on. Finally, I gave everything a coat of Satin varnish to help homogenise the finish and it actually made the reds that bit deeper which was nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rocks&quot;&gt;Rocks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paints used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rhinox Hide&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Abaddon black&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dawnstone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Administratum grey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rocks around the base, I base coated them in Rhinox Hide and gave it a thinned-down wash of Abaddon black . Finally, I dry brushed up through Dawnstone and Administratum grey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dirt&quot;&gt;Dirt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paints used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skavenblight Dinge&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stormvermin Fur&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Karak Stone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Doombull brown&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Castellan green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airbrushed over the base Skavenblight Dinge. Overspray is fine here since it just shows the dust blowing upwards so I didn’t bother masking any of the other parts. Nex a dry brush of Stormvermin Fur and Karak Stone. Finally, I applied patches of thinned-down Doombull Brown and Castellan Green in patches to modulate the colour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;weathering&quot;&gt;Weathering&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paints used&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highlight colour of the respective area&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dryad Bark&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Castellan Green&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Abteilung 502 Dark Rust&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Abteilung 502 Burnt Umber&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 days to go. Everything is in a position where I &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; hand it in as it stood but I knew I could make it more visually interesting. Particularly on white, chipping makes it easier to see the edges. I came in with a small bit of sponge and the highlight colour (white for the Doom Scythe, Wilde Rider red for the fin) and dabbed paint over the edges for the initial chipping. I come in with the highlight colour first as it is easier to correct mistakes that you don’t like than if you came straight in with the chipping colour. These highlights then became a guide to fill in with Dryad Bark – simply come in with a fine detail brush and fill in the blobs of the highlight paint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the fin, fine drips of castellan green were put around the patches of dirt and from some of the chips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tiny dots of the two Abteilung oil paints were also put all over the fin and rubbed in with a soft brush for just a very gentle colour modulation and to matte the fin back down. Finally, on both the Doom Scythe and the fin, small dots of burnt umber would be put all over and then drawn down using some white spirit into very fine drips. Because of the scale, I wanted these to be as thin as possible and fortunately, the beauty of oil paints is that if you mess up it can be removed almost instantly with no long-term effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then… it was go-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;golden-demon--feedback&quot;&gt;Golden Demon &amp;amp; Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/8-800-ec40a8c23.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/8-600-ec40a8c23.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/8-800-ec40a8c23.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/8-1000-ec40a8c23.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/9-800-c4235e067.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/9-600-c4235e067.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/9-800-c4235e067.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/9-1000-c4235e067.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row; margin:0;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/portrait-800-eed243609.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/portrait-600-eed243609.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/portrait-800-eed243609.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/portrait-1000-eed243609.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/2-800-e6c0482e0.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/2-600-e6c0482e0.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/2-800-e6c0482e0.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/2-1000-e6c0482e0.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row; margin:0;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/3-800-2c8bf227c.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/3-600-2c8bf227c.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/3-800-2c8bf227c.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/3-1000-2c8bf227c.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/4-800-b38fb11c6.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/4-600-b38fb11c6.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/4-800-b38fb11c6.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/4-1000-b38fb11c6.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/5-800-6c03ef4e1.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/5-600-6c03ef4e1.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/5-800-6c03ef4e1.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/5-1000-6c03ef4e1.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/6-800-37312e18f.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/6-600-37312e18f.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/6-800-37312e18f.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/6-1000-37312e18f.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/7-800-ddaff5cbe.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/7-600-ddaff5cbe.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/7-800-ddaff5cbe.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-07-20-golden-demon/7-1000-ddaff5cbe.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, I walked away with a Finalist’s pin. Of course, there was a bit of disappointment that I didn’t get further, but also as soon as I saw the other entrants it was clear quite how impressive the field was, and so I certainly wasn’t made to lose out to such excellent talent. After I collected my mini on the final day of Warhammer Fest, I just took the chance to ask people for feedback on what they thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I just happened to be walked past the cabinet I bumped into the King of Small Scale – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/tarominipainting/&quot;&gt;James Taro&lt;/a&gt;. I had to tell him how impressed I was that he got an entry together in 4 days and we naturally moved on to the topic of GD entries. Generally, he was very complimentary about the piece which was very lovely of him, and whether or not it was politeness it was quite nice the number of people who had seemed to note it when it was in the cabinets and mentioned how they liked it while I was walking around. Here are the main points James mentioned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More detail on the pilot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree with this point a lot. It was something that I needed to try and refine but I didn’t have the time to make mistakes coming towards the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tidy up the mounting point (part 1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see from the images above, I am still using the ball joint in the socket of the doom scythe. James suggested to try and hide this more such that you can’t see the pin. I had originally considered drilling a hole in the left wing and having that in contact with the top prong but I was lazy here. It’s definitely true that the entries which immerse themselves in a scene like mine are often positioned very well such that you can’t see how it’s attached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highlight the dents a bit more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Particularly the most distant edge with the brightest colour to help make them pop. Some of the dents did look a little bit flat bar the small amount of shading I had done on the closest edge, and I could definitely have made them look a bit deeper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do something more with the back of the base&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James suggested perhaps a small scene at the back like a soldier or body or something. At the very least there were large areas of black on the back of the fin that, while painted, weren’t visually interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/mamikonpaints/&quot;&gt;Mamikon Khatchikian&lt;/a&gt; also very kindly took a look, and since I had experience from his painting classes before I was also interested to show him what I had done since. I also liked to think I helped to take his mind off his incredible duel that was being judged at the time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tidy up the mounting point (part 2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, you can see some of the glue where I had painted over it and it would have been straightforward to scrape some of this up and clean that up a bit. I was probably a bit scared that it might look a bit inconsistent if I tried to repaint it but it’s definitely true that every detail needs to be immaculate to be in with a chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add more weathering to the black areas of the Doom Scythe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had weathered the white, but aside from the dents, there wasn’t really anything on the black of the Doom Scythe. I probably could have come in with at least some of the browns to make it look like it was gathering in the recesses more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the Cult of Paint meet up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/andywardle_artwork/&quot;&gt;Andy Wardle&lt;/a&gt; also very kindly cast his eye over it. The entire Cult of Paint team were generally really lovely and there were quite a few people sharing their pieces with one another. It was a great atmosphere. So Andy mentioned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Push the highlights/shadows more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you could see that I had put some directional lighting on the Doom Scythe, the darker side could be darker so that it reads more clearly in many different environments, rather than just accentuating the golden angle. Similarly,  he noted that he could see that I had tried to lighten where the black curved up slightly, but I could go further with this. I expressed reservations since I didn’t want it to look too blue, which he agreed with but mentioned how he typically highlights up past where he wants it then knocks the colour back with the base in order to make sure it reads correctly, which is certainly sound advice I will try in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certainly looking at the test model I realised that I had actually pushed the darker side of the white parts a lot more, and just hadn’t committed as much in the final thing. One thing I should probably do in future is take black and white photos of the miniature to see how much contrast there actually is in terms of colour but also light value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lighting on the dirt/rocks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put, there was no real indication of where the light was coming from on the rocks and base so this could have been made more obvious. In particular, he suggested in future using something like Milliput and carving some sharp edges so that there are clear surfaces that are in light and shadow. I did really like the texture of the bark and the rocks, so I’m not sure if I would sculpt the rocks for a Small Scale entry, but from my experience of doing the lighting on purity seals which have lots of folds, it certainly does let you have a really stark lighting if there are sharp edges. Perhaps I could have made them more like Necron crystals if I had tried that again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More detail on the pilot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pilot was largely just the brightest blue colour I had used and it needed more variation. In particular, Andy suggested that I start from the darkest base and highlight from underneath a bit more It might not have looked as bright overall but would have had more definition and would have been less washed out so should have still caught the eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the orange freehand to the black panels too&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this was more personal taste, and it probably would help tie the two sections of the Doom Scythe together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy also complimented the lack of backdrop, which was very vindicating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m really thankful to James, Mamikon and Andy for their thoughts. Initially, I was a bit anxious approaching people to ask for their thoughts since I didn’t want to bother anyone, but it was really lovely to see how many people were willing to spare their time to talk to people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four and a half seasons of Star Trek: The Next Generation later (what I was watching while just painting the model) I’m over the moon with the final result. While I may not have gone home with a trophy I got so much out of this whole experience. I’ve learnt so much about OSL and adding visual interest without having to convert everything. I hypnotise myself every time I look at it at the moment because it is by far the best piece I have ever made, and no one else gets to take this beauty home with them and own it forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are of course our own worst critic. The fact that the bit of Wave Serpent was built over 10 years ago and not to the best quality meant that there were some clear marks on the model from where glue had been scratched away, or had built up in other areas. All that being said I am really happy with the paint scheme itself and, while completely different from my original concept, I think turned out far better than I could have imagined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the feedback I got above I completely agree with. What’s reassuring is that most of it isn’t necessarily to do something differently but just to do it more i.e. more shadows, more highlights, more detail and range, which means that maybe with a bit more time I could go further with it. It was also good to see that the feedback was consistent which tells me that more time on those areas really would pay dividends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like the concept of the model. It’s likely I won’t enter this same piece again, largely because of the construction issues that you can see on the base, but in the future, I may revisit the composition and try again. At least on my second attempt, I will have a good reference of what I am aiming for which means that I don’t need to experiment as much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have made it this far, then thanks for reading all the way through. I would also love your feedback on the model too so please drop a comment below, or on my socials, or even DM if you have any questions and would like to chat about it further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m now going to take a well-earned break for a bit. But I’m tempted to do something more with my Scrap Demon entry now…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ollie</name></author><category term="Showcase" /><summary type="html">So here we are, my first Golden Demon entry in 10 years, and my first in the main competition. A lot has changed in that time – Large Scale has vanished, Small Scale has been added, and even all the trophies have had a re-design.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Warhammer Fest ‘23</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/review/2023/05/09/warhammerfest23.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Warhammer Fest ‘23" /><published>2023-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/review/2023/05/09/warhammerfest23</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/review/2023/05/09/warhammerfest23.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/IMG_8309-800-58f404f63.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/IMG_8309-600-58f404f63.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/IMG_8309-800-58f404f63.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/IMG_8309-1000-58f404f63.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Warhammer Fest has returned, and for the first time since Games Day 2013, I was finally free to attend and sample everything that GW has to offer. I had a blast of a time over the three days and it was an excellent way to spend my birthday weekend. That being said there is certainly a lot of room for improvement. This is also the first time I have entered Golden Demon since I was eligible for Youngbloods and I’m very happy with my finalist’s pin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be doing a separate write-up about my Golden Demon entry at a later date as I still need to take some proper pictures of my Doom Scythe since I only finished it on Friday morning. I’ll try and go through everything chronologically as I did it so that I don’t miss any details. I’ll also add some comments that I got from other people who were able to attend activities I did not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also a bit of a long one! But hopefully, you should be able to jump to where you are interested here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#day-1-and-the-hobby-challenge&quot;&gt;Day 1 and the Hobby Challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#day-2-and-the-great-queue&quot;&gt;Day 2 and the Great Queue&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#a-digression-on-tournaments&quot;&gt;A  Digression on Tournamens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#horus-heresy-and-old-world-reveals&quot;&gt;Horus Heresy and Old World Reveals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#hang-out-&amp;amp;-paint-live&quot;&gt;Hang out &amp;amp; Paint Live&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-golden-demon-cabinets&quot;&gt;The Golden Demon cabinets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#day-3-and-the-awards&quot;&gt;Day 3 and The Awards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#golden-demon-entrants&quot;&gt;Golden Demon Entrants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-1-and-the-hobby-challenge&quot;&gt;Day 1 and The Hobby Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 1 for me was booked up with the hobby challenge – you pick an event-exclusive miniature of your choice and jump into a massive pile of kits and sprues to build and paint something up in one day. This is effectively the latest incarnation of the Scrap Demon and the winner of each day of the Hobby challenge takes home the Scrap Demon trophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doors opened at 8 and my friends and I rocked up at about 9. I went to enter my GD entry so we got to the hobby challenge at 9:30 ish. There were still lots of great sprues available but it was evident that all the good stuff had been grabbed when doors open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of what was available were scenery kits and old push-fit models. It was a shame to see that there were actually a load of kill team kits and AoS Dominion sprues available at the start that some people had just picked up and put straight in their bags. I completely understand the need to and I’ll admit I’m much more speaking out of jealousy than anger but it definitely ruined the diversity of what could be made. That being said there were also some lovely people who were more than happy to share what they had and a massive shoutout &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/how2b_hsueh/&quot;&gt;Ben&lt;/a&gt; who was there from 8 until 6 studiously working on his minis and spreading around all the great stuff he wasn’t using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also a big box of pre-built minis which was really handy. Largely lots of push-fit pox walkers that you could build a horde around. This was a nice touch since it sped up a lot of time for people that really wanted to make something big – much like my friend Chris’ entry…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since there was such a large amount of AoS stuff, I decided to choose the Chaos model as my entry. I preferred the commissar but actually getting Tolgar Split-Eye out and putting it together really made me fall in love with the model and the box photos do not do it justice. The dynamic pose is something that you don’t see much unless a model is heavily converted so I bought an extra later on in the Fest since it gave me some inspiration for a future GD entry. Since there weren’t many kits that were getting the creative juices flowing I figures I would just paint a simple duel with Tolgar charging towards an AoS sorcerer (no idea what the actual kit is called) and just see how much I can get painted in a day – especially since I am notoriously slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/hobby_challenge-800-8cfaec571.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hobby Challenge results&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/hobby_challenge-600-8cfaec571.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/hobby_challenge-800-8cfaec571.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/hobby_challenge-1000-8cfaec571.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;My Hobby Challenge attempt&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After building our pieces they were then primed by the Event staff in either white or black. If you asked nicely they may have given it a zenithal prime for you too. It was about a 30 min wait for me which was completely fine since it was a prime opportunity to take a break and go and get some lunch. That being said, later in the day the security at the venue stopped the staff from priming so there became a big backlog while it was confirmed that GW had in fact cleared it with venue staff beforehand. Sadly Chris ended up waiting nearly an hour and a bit for his which was a shame. That being said, since the problem was simply the venue security being unsure it was allowed, I’m sure it wouldn’t have been a problem on the other days, nor should it be again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come 6 o’clock everyone had their entries on the table ready for judging and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/effie_elf_ears/&quot;&gt;Effie&lt;/a&gt; from the GW painting team came along to have a look. The winner got the Scrap Demon trophy and two runners-up also got some other prizes though I am not sure what they were. Unsurprisingly the people that got there early had some great pieces since they had more time to plan and realise their ideas, and rightly these people were rewarded for their endurance and effort. That being said there were some really fun ideas and conversions of the event mini, and genuinely impressive paint schemes for the time we had available and it was a shame they couldn’t all be recognised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m really happy with my entry. I got the chance to paint some models I wouldn’t normally pick up and I think I got them to a pretty good tabletop standard in effectively 5 hours of painting. I also had a good chance to try out more contrast paints which I wouldn’t have picked up otherwise. Chris took a slightly different approach with his duel and had the commissar fighting off a hoard of poxwalkers, which I think visually looked really good and was excellently executed, even if he did have trouble getting anything painted in time due to the priming delays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/hobby_challenge_Chris-800-86aed98c3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chris&apos; Hobby Challenge results&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/hobby_challenge_Chris-600-86aed98c3.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/hobby_challenge_Chris-800-86aed98c3.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/hobby_challenge_Chris-1000-86aed98c3.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Chris&apos; Hobby Challenge attempt&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I am glad about though is that I did bring some of my own paints and tools with me. I had them in my bag just in case something awful happened to my GD entry and it meant that I wasn’t scrounging around for paints all day. I did rightly have the piss taken out of me for being a try-hard when I pulled out my wet palette though. The paint selection was eclectic at best so having at least a couple of triads in my box with me meant I could actually challenge my speed painting rather than painting with a limited range of paints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hadn’t realised how much I missed just sitting down and painting with other people until the challenge. It was something I used to do all the time at my LGS and it’s just great to sit and chat as everyone is working on a different project, trading ideas, giving feedback and generally talking about what we like. Warhammer Fest was also the first time I had seen Chris, my friend who I was doing the Hobby Challenge with, in nearly 8 years. It was also the first time we had ever done any hobby together which was a really nice moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As will be a running theme throughout this write-up (I hesitate to call it a review), it is really the people I was with that made this a special event. I’ll admit that I’m not massively clued up on Warhammer content creators outside of the big painters, and people who regularly post tutorials that I pour over every detail of, but I felt really grateful to get to chat with PickleJarHobbies and LetsMakeitOrkie as we constantly made jokes about the excessively large number of pipe sprues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row; margin:0;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/IMG_8303-800-65895dae5.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/IMG_8303-600-65895dae5.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/IMG_8303-800-65895dae5.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/IMG_8303-1000-65895dae5.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/IMG_8304-800-a1e803910.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/IMG_8304-600-a1e803910.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/IMG_8304-800-a1e803910.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/IMG_8304-1000-a1e803910.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row; margin:0;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/IMG_8305-800-49587a2f1.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/IMG_8305-600-49587a2f1.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/IMG_8305-800-49587a2f1.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/IMG_8305-1000-49587a2f1.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/IMG_8306-800-e3d63759b.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/IMG_8306-600-e3d63759b.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/IMG_8306-800-e3d63759b.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/IMG_8306-1000-e3d63759b.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A selection of other entries&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So day 1 was a blast. I really felt like I was part of a community that day, and genuinely felt like I had made friends with people that I would love to see at conventions and meet-ups at a later date. To top it all off, my GD entry had already been judged and I had at least a finalists pin! I had also timed the day perfectly because the main complaint throughout the festival, but especially on the Saturday, was the queues. Even the queue to just buy things from the shop was nearly an hour long and it seems like I had avoided the worst of it by keeping myself busy on day 1. Nonetheless, for the rest of the weekend I had nothing else booked and so on Day 2 it was time to move on to the convention itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-2-and-the-great-queue&quot;&gt;Day 2 and The Great Queue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having been sat down quite comfortably all day on Day 1, Day 2 I was on my feet trying to get a feel for everything Warhammer Fest had to offer. Most of the morning was spent wandering around on the scavenger hunt, but I also used this as an excuse to talk to some of my favourite painters that were also at the convention. A particular shout out to Darren Latham, who is as lovely and supportive as you would expect, and Marco Frisoni who was incredibly friendly and happy to talk about his work and what he had planned for the future. It’s unusual having watched so many hours of these painter’s (and others) videos because in my mind I do hold them as celebrities in some way. It was really lovely just to get to hang out with them and realise that in fact everyone is just human and they really do just love what they do and enjoy talking about their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was planning on having a go on the 10th edition tables, but the queues for this were incredibly long, often more than a couple of hours to just play a round of 10th edition. Something I heard from a lot of people is that they didn’t necessarily want to be the person rolling the dice or making decisions, they just wanted to hear what was being said to get a feel for the rules. Since there was only 5 tables, this whole activity should certainly have had much better capacity. That being said a massive hats off to Nick Bayton and the rest of the GW team running these tables – I cannot imagine how exhausting it must have been to be running games for nearly 10 hours a day for 3 days straight with what felt like no drop in enthusiasm. Any criticism here is at the logistics and definitely not the incredible staff manning these stalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the rest of the hall, after chatting plenty of shit to Chris and Matt in the queue for the Squigapult, I didn’t make a fool of myself and got 2/3 winning a Warhammer Fest poster. Not a huge prize though given they were also being given out for free if you bought anything from the store…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right next to the Squigapult was the Titan Owner’s Club who were playing a full-scale size game of Adeptus Titanicus. It was admittedly very cool, but as someone that doesn’t play the game, the novelty wore off very quickly, especially since I don’t think spectators could actually play. Nonetheless, the titan display was very well done, and bravo to the Titan Owner’s Club for keeping up their enthusiasm for three days as I constantly heard shouts of “ENGINE KIILLLLL” whenever a titan was defeated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next to the main hall was also a great stand where all the cosplayers were present. So many full-sized space marines, including a Warmaster Horus. I’m happy that GW gave them an exclusive space to show off and support their work. I also took the opportunity to chat with some of teh painters I had followed online and just generally let them know how great they are. Particular shoutout to the ‘Eavy Metal legend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/darrenlatham/&quot;&gt;Darren Latham&lt;/a&gt; and OSL/Oil paints master &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/njm_marcofrisoni/&quot;&gt;Marco Frisoni&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/necron-800-2bb683cab.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/necron-600-2bb683cab.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/necron-800-2bb683cab.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/necron-1000-2bb683cab.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/Marco-800-0fd4dede1.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/Marco-600-0fd4dede1.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/Marco-800-0fd4dede1.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/Marco-1000-0fd4dede1.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-digression-on-tournaments&quot;&gt;A digression on Tournaments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also took the time to have a look around the tournament tables. My friend John had been playing in the 40k GT all weekend and I thought it a good opportunity to have a look at people’s armies. From what I heard from John and other people who had done gaming events, the competitive and casual tournaments were incredibly slickly organised. From speaking to the tournament judges too, apparently the team that organises a lot of competitive events in the US had been shipped over to run them. There were also screens around the outside of the hall televising the Twitch stream of the top tables with some great commentary on the tactics. As someone that hasn’t played 40k properly since 7th edition I never realised how detailed tactics could actually get but it all sounded incredibly insightful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A particular shout out to the American announcer who was generally making sure the tournaments went smoothly and also occasionally announcing things for the Fest as a whole such as GD updates. He had the timbre of a slick radio host and it always made me smile whenever there was an update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/me_and_John-800-0d1d3f804.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/me_and_John-600-0d1d3f804.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/me_and_John-800-0d1d3f804.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/me_and_John-1000-0d1d3f804.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;John and I taking a well earned break on the final day&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;horus-heresy-and-old-world-reveals&quot;&gt;Horus Heresy and Old World Reveals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, back to what &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; was up to… it was reaching 1:20 now, and the announcements that I was interested in, namely Horus Heresy and the Old World, were coming up at 14:00. Since I didn’t have anything else pressing to do I went to the queue to get into the hall and I’m glad I went when I did. Even 40 minutes before I only just got in as the hall reached capacity. It was a long wait, but it was really lovely just striking up a conversation with the people in the queue and talking about how they got into the hobby and what they were looking forward to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Tomb Kings player, this was great news for me. Being able to see new TK models for the first time in 10 years got me really excited. The atmosphere in the room was great and the Q&amp;amp;A afterwards was wonderfully insightful. The main headlines were to expect rules for all 8th edition Fantasy models, but only the factions present during the War of the Three Emperors would be regularly supported with new minis for now. It was interesting how candid GW were about how their support for the game will be based on how popular the rules and models will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hang-out--paint-live&quot;&gt;Hang out &amp;amp; Paint Live&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to stay around in the auditorium for the Hang out &amp;amp; Paint session that was happening straight after. I don’t normally tune in to the Twitch stream but seemed like a great place to chill and just listen to people talk about the hobby. It wasn’t as well attended as all the announcement seminars of course, but it was a lovely intimate hour of just asking questions and talking about painting with WarhammerTV presenter &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/em_the_paint_freak/&quot;&gt;Em Robinson&lt;/a&gt;. Adam Troke was on hand to run about the auditorium with the microphone and he did a stellar job of compering the auditorium events all weekend with excellent time management precision, quick-witted humour and lovely additional insights and his own thoughts on people’s questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the hidden gem of Warhammer Fest and a great way to escape the hustle and bustle of the main hall. It would have been lovely if it was just a bit longer and felt like when we used to be able to chat with the Design team in the days of old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-golden-demon-cabinets&quot;&gt;The Golden Demon cabinets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was coming to about 16:30 now and the crowds were largely dying down. By this point the first round of judging was completed in GD so I took the opportunity to take a look at the entries. I have put a gallery at the bottom of the post with all my pics of entries. Going around the cabinets it was great to hear people’s thoughts on entries as well as have people point out what they had done. I had a blast speaking to a couple of Youngbloods entrants and we chatted about the stuff I had entered in Youngbloods over 10 years ago now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s always so different to be able to see these miniatures in person. As well as seeing the incredible talent on display and details that may not be pictured by miniatures, you can see the brushstrokes which certainly helps to de-mystify the process that people have taken to make them. I always have a personal love for the simple pieces that tell a great story, or painting styles and colour palettes that are different from what one typically expects from a GW miniature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A particular curiosity was that non-finalists (i.e. those without green stickers) could collect their miniatures from 16:00, but while I was looking around the cabinets, green stickers were still being added to some entries. It’s a shame to think some people who had collected their entries straight away might have missed out on a pin because of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, I could always spend hours staring at GD entries, and I was glad I went later in the afternoon as many of the crowds had died down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/801-800-cfb143a67.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;GD entry&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/801-600-cfb143a67.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/801-800-cfb143a67.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/801-1000-cfb143a67.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;My Entry in the cabinet!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-3-and-the-awards&quot;&gt;Day 3 and The Awards&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have finally made it to day three. The rest of my friends were involved in the Doubles tournament so I was left to occupy myself. Unfortunately, there really wasn’t that much left to do that I hadn’t done already. I played the trial of Boltgun, which was fun, but only killed 20 mins at the start of the day. So I sat around for a bit before I decided to go pick up my GD entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a finalists pin which I was super happy about, and I realised there were a lot of artists hanging around so I took a chance to just ask people for their thoughts on my piece and suggestions on how I can improve. I will give them all individual shout-outs when I do my write-up on the entry itself. But for now a huge thank you to all of you for being so lovely and approachable as well as giving me some great advice on what to focus on for next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed on Instagram that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/cultofpaint/&quot;&gt;Cult of Paint&lt;/a&gt; team were also having a meet-up at midday so figured I would swing by and have a chat. Once again, like a broken record, the best people to have a chat with. All of the team had their minis with them and were just open to chatting about Cult of Paint, their work, and the competition in general. Really insightful and I got chatting with plenty of other GD entrants and we all shared our work and discussed them. I actually thought this was a highlight of the event as I could just chat with other like-minded painters and we could trade tips and ideas on how we did everything we did. I ended up being there for an hour and a bit, so quickly went to grab some food before joining the queue an hour and a bit early for the GD awards ceremony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that we didn’t need to queue for so long as most people had in fact gone home by that point in the Fest and so the hall was never at capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way the award ceremony works had changed a lot since I last entered in 2013. Back then, all the winners knew who they were before the ceremony, and so there was no anxiety. Speaking to several previous winners this apparently changed a few years ago such that the commended entries don’t find out until the winner was called on stage which sounds anxiety-inducing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, GW decided to take this one step further and get all the commended entries on stage for each category and announce the winners while they were up there. I understand the thinking behind this because it gives recognition to all of those who may not actually win a trophy. Since the standard of GD has increased so much over the last few years it is important to make sure that people who do incredible work are given their time to shine. On a practical note, it also made it much easier in the auditorium to give out the awards as there was less awkward shuffling, but at the same time, I have a lot of problems with it. In fact, by the sounds of the groans from the entire audience, especially the commended entrants themselves, this was not a popular move. I also thought that making the Youngbloods go up first was definitely not the right way to go about it just seconds after springing this format change on them. All that beings said, the love that those Youngbloods entrants got from the crowd was so great to see and I’ll admit I’m very jealous of their skill at such a young age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are understandably a lot of popular painters in GD that do well and rightly deserve recognition. But at the same time, there are a lot of nervous people (myself included) that would find it pretty intimidating sharing a stage with these great artists, let alone when the crowd starts chanting people’s names before the results have even been announced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the simplest thing for GW to have done would have been just to go back to the original format of letting people know beforehand. I really worry there is the potential for someone to have a bad reaction while on stage and that’s only going to reflect badly on GW when that inevitably happens. By all means, then get the Gold winners up for the Slayer Sword announcement, and also invite the commended entrants and winners in each category, but once people have had a chance to process their nerves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now all of this negativity should do nothing to detract from the actual achievement of the incredible artists who won Demons on Monday. Every single one was incredibly well deserved and Alberto’s Slayer Sword winning entry was breathtaking. I’m really glad none of the audience followed the instruction to stay silent until the sword was lifted, you could not keep a lid on how blown away everyone in the room was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also really happy to see that Warhammer Community are publishing the commended entries as well. The standard of this competition has reached so high that any of the commended entries could have gone home with a trophy on any other day. I also really like the idea floating around on social media of bringing back finalist medals for the commended entries. These could then be handed out with the trophies and I think it would remove some of the awkwardness if you are one of the two people on stage not to get anything for the smaller categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, after that it was time to collect my things and go. Just as I was leaving I had the opportunity to speak to Angelo di Chello - a personal hero of mine since he won the Slayer Sword the first time I ever entered, and what a wonderfully sincere man he is. Apparently, his Bronze winning entry was his first try and NMM in a competition?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a really incredible weekend and got the chance to speak to loads of great artists and creators. I’ll be speaking more about the specific advice I was given when I actually go through my GD piece in a separate post. But it did feel that Warhammer Fest was great &lt;em&gt;despite&lt;/em&gt; GW’s best efforts. If you hadn’t booked anything extra at the event, it was very easy to run out of things to do, and queues aside, you could have got through everything in an hour or two. Some of my group on the second day just brought their armies with them and had some games on spare tournament tables, which the tournament organisers were more than happy to facilitate. In future, I will definitely bring an army up with me too even if I don’t do the tournaments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would also be interested to know what the painting classes were like. Despite the main topics, there was very little detail on what models students would be painting or what they should expect to achieve by the end of the class. It did seem that every student got to pick 10 citadel paints to take with them as a part of the class though which does make them really good value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall it just felt like there needed to be more. No design studio members were present, no additional vendors, nothing from Black Library and just very little actual interaction with GW itself. It was fun because I happened to get talking with so many other attendees. I feel like GW needs to be more of a facilitator at these events rather than be everything. Very much focus on GW products and minis for sure, but allow external artists to host classes as they do at Adepticon, get Black Library authors and GW’s ‘conventional’ artists in to give seminars and talks on their work. Why not even get some of the writers/actors/designers from the Warhammer+ TV shows to do panels akin to ComicCon?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought my ticket without details as GW had hyped up that this was going to be the greatest thing ever, and while it was better than the last Games Day in 2013, it very much felt like it was oversold. Games Day 2013 was a big shop with Golden Demon and Armies on Parade. Warhammer Fest was a big shop with Golden Demon and some games, but it was better because I got to speak with other attendees whose work I knew and loved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet… even after all that… I would totally buy a ticket again straight away next year. I got to be a part of a community that I haven’t been able to interact with in so long, and I’m really happy that I made the most of my time in Manchester to share what so many people clearly love. Let’s face it, I’m by no means a big-time creator, I just have this tiny corner of the internet to record my thoughts and make sure I don’t forget anything I have done, if people happen to also read it then even better. But this weekend I really felt like I had my place as just this guy with a tiny doom scythe who enjoys telling people how great they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So thanks to everyone for making my 26th Birthday so special. Now finally let’s get to that sweet sweet GD gallery:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;golden-demon-entrants&quot;&gt;Golden Demon Entrants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;pig&quot; data-source=&quot;/assets/images/2023-05-09-warhammerfest23/gallery.json&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>ollie</name></author><category term="Review" /><summary type="html">So Warhammer Fest has returned, and for the first time since Games Day 2013, I was finally free to attend and sample everything that GW has to offer. I had a blast of a time over the three days and it was an excellent way to spend my birthday weekend. That being said there is certainly a lot of room for improvement. This is also the first time I have entered Golden Demon since I was eligible for Youngbloods and I’m very happy with my finalist’s pin!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Éomer, Marshal of the Riddermark</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/showcase/2023/02/12/eomer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Éomer, Marshal of the Riddermark" /><published>2023-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/showcase/2023/02/12/eomer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/showcase/2023/02/12/eomer.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/both_landscape-800-aca959734.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/both_landscape-600-aca959734.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/both_landscape-800-aca959734.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/both_landscape-1000-aca959734.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It really has been a while since I have posted any updates. I promise I actually did some painting in 2022 but for various reasons, I have still been experimenting and playing around with stuff to the point where I haven’t got anything finished. But, over Christmas, I had a bit of time on my hands and wanted to paint up Éomer as a gift for my flatmate. So within 2 days of 2023, I had already beaten my 2022 record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said, this has actually been painted up as a gift for my flatmate. He is part of a Lord of the Rings Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons game and his character is a Rohirim. Part of his character is that his plume has been cut off, hence the slight modification on the helmet. Honestly, this has been the most fun I have had painting in a long time. I think much of it is to do with the fact it is a one-off mini so I don’t need to think about full cohesion with an army, and there is so much detail on the new plastic LOTR characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row; margin:0;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/mounted1-800-0809808bd.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/mounted1-600-0809808bd.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/mounted1-800-0809808bd.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/mounted1-1000-0809808bd.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/mounted2-800-337d51d09.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/mounted2-600-337d51d09.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/mounted2-800-337d51d09.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/mounted2-1000-337d51d09.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row; margin:0;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/mounted3-800-58e9be981.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/mounted3-600-58e9be981.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/mounted3-800-58e9be981.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/mounted3-1000-58e9be981.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/mounted4-800-bdec4c86b.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/mounted4-600-bdec4c86b.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/mounted4-800-bdec4c86b.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/mounted4-1000-bdec4c86b.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row; margin:0;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/foot1-800-481737107.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/foot1-600-481737107.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/foot1-800-481737107.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/foot1-1000-481737107.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/foot2-800-31ad549a8.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/foot2-600-31ad549a8.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/foot2-800-31ad549a8.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/foot2-1000-31ad549a8.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row; margin:0;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/foot3-800-71f684650.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/foot3-600-71f684650.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/foot3-800-71f684650.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/foot3-1000-71f684650.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/foot4-800-a0fcaff64.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/foot4-600-a0fcaff64.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/foot4-800-a0fcaff64.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2023-02-12-eomer/foot4-1000-a0fcaff64.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The model was largely painted in line with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CmYYTqHxwjM&amp;amp;ab_channel=Warhammer&quot;&gt;tutorial by Nick Bayton&lt;/a&gt; but I made a few changes just to tie some of the colours together a bit better. If you are using the helmeted version I would also suggest painting the face before adding the top half of the helmet… that was a pain…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;armour&quot;&gt;Armour&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tutorial suggests that Doombull brown should be the colour of choice for the armour. It looks perfect in the tutorial but didn’t seem to quite be red enough for my liking in real life, so I actually used a 50:50 mix of Khorne red and Doombull brown. The rest of the highlights should be in line with what’s suggested&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-mighty-steed&quot;&gt;The Mighty Steed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The horse I diverged considerably more from. In particular, I didn’t want to have to spend ages trying to blend and highlight up the colours because I knew I would make a mess of it. I also preferred a more earthy grey for the horse since it is a living breathing thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin with, I airbrushed the basecoats on the horse, focusing more from directly above using:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Abaddon black&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Corvus black&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skavenblight Dinge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then went back with Abaddon black to reinforce the shadows just glazing it into some of the more well-defined areas. Finally, I added a highlight of Stormvermin fur to the defined raised edges. If I was going to spend more time on this I might have considered trying to use the brush more to get more of a fur texture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the head, this is largely in line with the tutorial except I shaded the face using:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Karak Stone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stormvermin Fur&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skavenblight Dinge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think Apothecary white has too much of a blue tone for it to look natural with the rest of the horse and using the colours of the black fur helps to tie the head to the rest of the model a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;base&quot;&gt;Base&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Call me old fashioned, but I’ve just never really gotten along with the texture paints and I much prefer using sand and painting that instead as it gives more control. After base coating the sand in Rhinox Hide, I then dry brushed the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Steel Legion Drab&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Baneblade brown&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Karak Stone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stones were also base coated in Rhinox Hide with the rest of the base, and following a thin wash of Abaddon black was dry brushed with Dawnstone and Adminstratum grey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rims are the classic Steel Legion Drab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This piece was honestly the perfect way to spend my Christmas break (aside from the time I was with my family of course). Got plenty of motivation to paint again, which is pretty good given I have a Golden Demon entry to paint… but more on that another time. I also got to grips with some contrast paints a bit more, which admittedly I don’t use that much. That being said I think the effect of the bronze chainmail really speaks for itself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ollie</name></author><category term="Showcase" /><summary type="html">It really has been a while since I have posted any updates. I promise I actually did some painting in 2022 but for various reasons, I have still been experimenting and playing around with stuff to the point where I haven’t got anything finished. But, over Christmas, I had a bit of time on my hands and wanted to paint up Éomer as a gift for my flatmate. So within 2 days of 2023, I had already beaten my 2022 record.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Painting faces with Noki Studios</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/review/2021/12/02/noki-class-faces.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Painting faces with Noki Studios" /><published>2021-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/review/2021/12/02/noki-class-faces</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/review/2021/12/02/noki-class-faces.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-12-02-niko-class-faces/face_landscape-800-2bbd3032d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Miniature face&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-12-02-niko-class-faces/face_landscape-600-2bbd3032d.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-12-02-niko-class-faces/face_landscape-800-2bbd3032d.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-12-02-niko-class-faces/face_landscape-1000-2bbd3032d.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after how much I enjoyed &lt;a href=&quot;/review/2021/10/17/noki-class.html&quot;&gt;my last class&lt;/a&gt; I could hardly say no when I saw Mamikon announce his face painting one. From last time I already knew that whatever preconceived notions I had of what I was capable of and how I thought the best way to go about faces would be blown out of the water - and I’m so glad I was right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bringing-the-right-kit&quot;&gt;Bringing the right kit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This certainly won’t be as extensive as my previous NMM post, not least because I would likely be repeating all the excellent things I said last time, and also I sadly didn’t get as many pics… In any case, like last time the class started promptly at 12:00pm at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.badmooncafe.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Bad Moon Cafe&lt;/a&gt;. Unlike last time, at precisely 12:02pm I realised that I had left my wet palette out on the kitchen counter to dry out before transporting it and was thus left palette-less for the day. Fortunately, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/hivecityblues/&quot;&gt;Mo&lt;/a&gt;, one of the other students, kindly lent me his normal palette, and then, like a knight in shining armour &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/fnd_studios_/&quot;&gt;Zak&lt;/a&gt;, who I met at the original class, arrived and let me share some space on his - thanks to you both!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to the class, Mamikon had prepped all the heads that we would be painting, once again we all received two bits to try out. To save us time just simply base coating the heads in the same flat colours in the initial steps, everything was pre-base coated in a suitably fleshly colour, so we could jump right into practising the highlighting and shading of the face and get to work bringing the piece to life. I only focussed on one head this time just because there weren’t as many fancy effects I wanted to try out, but more variations of heads for the bitz box is always welcome, and several other people did have a go at both as a ‘practice’ and ‘final’ piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-gateway-to-the-soul&quot;&gt;The Gateway to the soul&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the 6 hour class (including some breaks for lunch and grabbing drinks etc.), we took the entire head from start to finish. Beginning with an initial mid-tone to lighten things up a bit, adding warmth to the recesses and around the eye and accentuating the scars and sharpest features. I’m particularly satisfied with how the eyes came out, and the addition of stubble around the mouth and on top of the head helped balance out the tone and realism of the whole piece. One thing I particularly felt like I learnt more about was approaching how to think about real objects (in this case someone’s skin) and consider which highlights and shades are due to the lighting conditions vs the history of the object such as the age of any scars - it certainly got me thinking more about tone modulation for other areas of painting and I do genuinely think it will have an effect on how I approach minis in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I think the results speak for themselves. They say the face is meant to be the focal point of any mini, but even without a body I keep getting distracted by staring at this tiny head on my desk, proud of the fact that this is something I am capable of. I will likely even stick it onto one of my space marines when I get round to finishing them. While both classes were great, I came out of this one with my mind buzzing about so many ideas for display minis that I have had over the last couple of weeks anyway and this has absolutely given me the confidence to give them a crack (once I’ve at least finished my first squad of Sons of Medusa…).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that I also realised I missed from my days when I would just sit in my local GW painting, was just talking about the hobby with like-minded people while we worked away on our own pieces. As well as the excellent tutelage from Mamikon, everyone in the class was exchanging tips and cheats that helped them with various aspects of the hobby and giving each other feedback on things we were working on as well as our thoughts on the latest competitions and events. It’s a sense of community that I haven’t actively been a part of for a very long time, and it definitely beats sitting at home with a random Netflix show on in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always it has been an absolute pleasure. If you are interested in Mamikon’s work, be sure to keep an eye on his &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MamikonPaints&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/nokipaintingstudio/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; as that is where you will likely hear about more classes soon!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ollie</name></author><category term="Review" /><summary type="html">So after how much I enjoyed my last class I could hardly say no when I saw Mamikon announce his face painting one. From last time I already knew that whatever preconceived notions I had of what I was capable of and how I thought the best way to go about faces would be blown out of the water - and I’m so glad I was right.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Compendium&amp;amp;#58 Volume 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/review/2021/10/31/compendium.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Compendium&amp;amp;#58 Volume 1" /><published>2021-10-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-10-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/review/2021/10/31/compendium</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/review/2021/10/31/compendium.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/cover_angle-800-c09c4eb15.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Compendium cover&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/cover_angle-600-c09c4eb15.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/cover_angle-800-c09c4eb15.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/cover_angle-1000-c09c4eb15.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Impulse purchase definitely isn’t the right word here, but I certainly don’t think I have progressed from seeing something to buying it quite as quickly as when the kickstarter went live for Compendium: Volume 1. Produced by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theminiaturescompendium.com/&quot;&gt;The Miniatures Compendium&lt;/a&gt; and launched on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/miniaturescompendium/compendium-volume-one/description&quot;&gt;kickstarter&lt;/a&gt; back in March 2021, it is clear from start to finish that this is a labour of love. This mighty tome collects Golden Demon winners from over the past 30 years with additional commentary and even works in progress photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;max-width: 450px; height: auto;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/cover-800-3bda7208f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Compendium cover&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/cover-600-3bda7208f.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/cover-800-3bda7208f.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/cover-1000-3bda7208f.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Cover artwork designed by Orniris Terensi&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you that don’t follow The Miniatures Compendium on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/thegoldendemoncompendium/&quot;&gt;their instagram&lt;/a&gt;, for years it has been an incredible archive of past and present Golden Demon winners, with every person they follow being a Golden Demon winning artist. This volume is a culmination of nearly 4 years of work, covering 94 miniatures from 54 different artists all presented in a gorgeous 320-page hardback volume with additional art by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/orniris/&quot;&gt;Orniris Terensi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/inside-800-bf21d3437.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bretonnian knight&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/inside-600-bf21d3437.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/inside-800-bf21d3437.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/inside-1000-bf21d3437.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Some WIP shots from Jose Carlos Reverte&apos;s Bretonnian Knight&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going all the way back to 1988, it is super interesting to see how painting styles have evolved and improved as the hobby has grown and its quite a nice trip down memory lane seeing winners that I was able to see back when I went to GamesDay. Each entry is presented over several pages, with brand new high res photography to really capture every detail and every angle of the model that you don’t normally see on websites like &lt;a href=&quot;http://demonwinner.free.fr/&quot;&gt;Demon Winner&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://golden-demon.com/&quot;&gt;Golden Demon&lt;/a&gt;. The incredible resolution and detail in the images also works to make the entries feel so much more attainable - these images are the closest I am going to get to actually holding them in my hands, to the point where you can start to see the brush strokes and how the overall finish is constructed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/soper-680-6e9eaf44c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;David Soper&apos;s Eldar Warrior&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/soper-600-6e9eaf44c.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/soper-680-6e9eaf44c.jpg 680w&quot; /&gt;

	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;David Soper&apos;s 1988 Eldar Warrior&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/penaut-680-5d64aafff.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Maxime Penaud&apos;s Dankhold Troggoth&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/penaut-600-5d64aafff.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/penaut-680-5d64aafff.jpg 680w&quot; /&gt;

	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Maxime Penaud&apos;s 2019 Dankhold Troggoth&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the miniatures also have an excellent commentary from the artist themselves about the process and story behind the models. Since so many of the entries are often heavily converted its hard to know where us mere mortals could even start by creating such incredible pieces, but understanding the thought process, often alongside an image of the unpainted model further helps to show how skilled a sculptor these people are, and what materials were used. A particular favourite of mine is seeing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/iagop_works/&quot;&gt;Iago Pineda’s&lt;/a&gt; 2003 Youngbloods entry followed by his 2004 Slayer Sword winning entry (At the age of 15!) and the process behind how his styles improved and changed over the intervening year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, my absolute highlight is the pictures of Roman Lappat’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://massivevoodoo.blogspot.com/2013/11/the-last-light.html&quot;&gt;The Last Light&lt;/a&gt; diorama that won the 2013 German Slayer Sword. I fell in love with this piece when I saw it on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://massivevoodoo.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Massive Voodoo&lt;/a&gt; blog nearly 8 years ago, and hands down has to be the greatest Slayer Sword winner of all time. It is all in all a great trip down memory lane to see models that I remember reading about in White Dwarf and online. However, it is a bit annoying that the only place that says the year, category and position is in the contents, so I keep needing to flick back and forth to get all the information about the entries as I’m looking. But to be honest it’s really the miniatures themselves that we care about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/last_light-800-5955b3dc6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Last Light Diorama&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/last_light-600-5955b3dc6.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/last_light-800-5955b3dc6.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-31-compendium/last_light-1000-5955b3dc6.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The Last Light by Roman Lappat&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going all the way up to the most recent Golden Demon competitions in 2019 (hopefully, with a new one soon), I think like many people, the fact that this book is titled “Volume 1” hopefully hints that more are on the way. The kickstarter pledges are still being fulfilled but it looks like this should be completed by the end of November. I’ll admit it is quite cool as a kickstarter backer to have my name listed in the back, and particularly flattering that several people messaged me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/ifthehuefits.blog/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; thinking my name was there because I had previously won. Unfortunately, I don’t know if additional copies will be available at a later date. I certainly hope so, and if it is then you really must get a copy - even my flatmate and friends who aren’t Warhammer-savvy have had a flick through and marvelled at some of the incredible work on display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing all the high-res pictures makes me want to re-do the images for of my last Golden Demon entry - the 2013 Youngbloods which I did actually get a finalists pin for. However, I think the model is in one of my cases back in Lincolnshire, so perhaps a task for another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row; margin:0;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/warhammer/nurgle_lord_2-800-95b9b4e7d.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/warhammer/nurgle_lord_2-600-95b9b4e7d.jpg 600w, /generated/images/warhammer/nurgle_lord_2-800-95b9b4e7d.jpg 800w, /generated/images/warhammer/nurgle_lord_2-1000-95b9b4e7d.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/warhammer/nurgle_lord_4-800-033ec9f14.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/warhammer/nurgle_lord_4-600-033ec9f14.jpg 600w, /generated/images/warhammer/nurgle_lord_4-800-033ec9f14.jpg 800w, /generated/images/warhammer/nurgle_lord_4-1000-033ec9f14.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row; margin:0;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/warhammer/nurgle_lord_3-800-da7f06ddd.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/warhammer/nurgle_lord_3-600-da7f06ddd.jpg 600w, /generated/images/warhammer/nurgle_lord_3-800-da7f06ddd.jpg 800w, /generated/images/warhammer/nurgle_lord_3-1000-da7f06ddd.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/warhammer/nurgle_lord_1-800-36ebb2d67.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/warhammer/nurgle_lord_1-600-36ebb2d67.jpg 600w, /generated/images/warhammer/nurgle_lord_1-800-36ebb2d67.jpg 800w, /generated/images/warhammer/nurgle_lord_1-1000-36ebb2d67.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;My 2013 Youngbloods entry&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But who knows, if there is a volume 2 then I think its a pretty good aspiration to one day be included in these pages, and I think I’ve come a pretty long way in the 8 years since.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ollie</name></author><category term="Review" /><summary type="html">Impulse purchase definitely isn’t the right word here, but I certainly don’t think I have progressed from seeing something to buying it quite as quickly as when the kickstarter went live for Compendium: Volume 1. Produced by The Miniatures Compendium and launched on kickstarter back in March 2021, it is clear from start to finish that this is a labour of love. This mighty tome collects Golden Demon winners from over the past 30 years with additional commentary and even works in progress photos.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Non-Metallic Metals Class with Noki Studios</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/review/2021/10/17/noki-class.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Non-Metallic Metals Class with Noki Studios" /><published>2021-10-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-10-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/review/2021/10/17/noki-class</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/review/2021/10/17/noki-class.html">&lt;figure&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/both_l-800-3dd67a1ed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Non-metallic metal swords&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/both_l-600-3dd67a1ed.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/both_l-800-3dd67a1ed.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/both_l-1000-3dd67a1ed.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to think (and I certainly hope you would agree) that I’m a fairly good painter, or at least I certainly know my way around a paintbrush. However, one of my main problems with improving my skills is that it’s rare that tutorials and videos that I am watching apply directly to what it is I am trying to do - be it different colours, models or just knowing when to use it. This means that if something ends up not quite how I was expecting, it can make it hard to specifically diagnose whether it’s my technique, the colours I’m using or how I’m actually applying the new skill. For years I’ve wanted to go to painting classes to try and alleviate this issue and also have the chance to talk directly to people that I &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; can do what I’m trying to achieve. Unfortunately, due to logistics, cost or more recently a global pandemic I’ve never had a chance - until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been following Mamkion of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/nokipaintingstudio/&quot;&gt;Noki Painting Studio&lt;/a&gt; for a while, so I was really happy to see when he was advertising several different classes over the next few months and jumped at the chance to do his non-metallic metal (NMM) one. Communication beforehand was great, and it was made very clear what materials and tools we would need along with an advised paints list, so with my bags packed, brushes in hand, I jumped on the tube and made my way to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.badmooncafe.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Bad Moon Cafe&lt;/a&gt;, our venue for the six-hour session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/showcase-800-781f18a3d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;miniature showcase&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/showcase-600-781f18a3d.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/showcase-800-781f18a3d.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/showcase-1000-781f18a3d.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Some of the incredible display minis Mamikon brought along&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll admit, &lt;em&gt;initially&lt;/em&gt; I was a bit disappointed when I turned up and found out we would be painting swords. Like a walking &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dunning%E2%80%93Kruger_effect&quot;&gt;Dunning-Kruger&lt;/a&gt; graph at the peak of Mount Stupid, foolishly I had assumed I knew most of what there was to know about the actual recipes used for non-metallic metal, and was worried that I wouldn’t get as much out of the class as I hoped. What I was hoping to learn was the application, that is, how to take a model (or part thereof) and know where to place the reflections and highlights without having to look at images of work from people that have done NMM on similar models. It turns out that (a) I would learn a lot about application I never realised (b) colour and the application were more linked than I originally thought (c) there is no point trying to run until you’ve mastered how to walk. To strain this metaphor a bit further, I quickly realised all I had done was just put on some shoes and assumed that’s all there was to it, without actually trying to stand up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-slope-of-enlightenment&quot;&gt;The Slope of Enlightenment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, class underway, we begin with a brief chat about the techniques involved and started with a fairly straightforward NMM sword. Mamikon had also prepped a really good sequence of swords which showed full step by step so we knew at least what to aim for or expect at the end of each stage. It was great to get one on one feedback at each of the stages and this was tailored to the different levels of each student. It was particularly helpful to have the confidence that blemishes and mistakes are fine, and in fact, later stages will naturally mask them or they can be turned more into features that make the sword look more battle-worn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/examples-800-409ef0508.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Non-metallic metal swords step-by-step&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/examples-600-409ef0508.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/examples-800-409ef0508.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/examples-1000-409ef0508.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;We used this example set to see how each stage builds on the previous&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the foundation of the ‘standard’ NMM sword ready, we then started adding glazes and what I can best describe as a lens-flare effect - it felt insane to be using red, green and yellow on what was meant to be a silver sword, but honestly, I think the results speak for themselves! With everyone getting two swords each to play with, there was plenty of room for experimentation, and it also meant everyone could go at their own pace and try out multiple styles or just focus on getting one piece looking really great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a quick 45-minute lunch break (which for me was closer to an hour after finding out a nearby store had Imperium magazine #5 in stock with the exclusive captain) we were back and then on to trying gold. This was the part that I was really interested in as we were painting the hand and other features on the sword which had more complex surfaces that interacted with the lights in different ways. Having now done the main blade of the sword I felt much better equipped tackling the other bits of the part (parts of the bit?) that I don’t think I would have been as confident in had we just jumped into complex surfaces. Being able to ask not just what should be done but &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; really helped improve the depth of my understanding and a lot of explanation was done in the context of some incredible display models that were brought along so we could see, for example, how and why you might shift around the reflections on a hand in different scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/glaive-800-1e56405db.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/glaive-600-1e56405db.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/glaive-800-1e56405db.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/glaive-1000-1e56405db.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/longsword-800-61971da20.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/longsword-600-61971da20.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/longsword-800-61971da20.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/longsword-1000-61971da20.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I had a really excellent time, and I am so happy with how my sword turned out - Mamikon is an excellent teacher and very patient in answering all my questions. At £80 for six hours, I think this session really was a steal. Everyone else in the class was also really lovely and incredibly supportive of one another. It’s been a long time since I have painted with other people around, and it was great just to have a chat about what sort of projects people are working on, how they find certain tools and paints and just where they are from. Particular shout out to Zak from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/fnd_studios_/&quot;&gt;Faith and Damnation studios&lt;/a&gt; and David at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/diddy_miniatures/&quot;&gt;Diddy Miniatures&lt;/a&gt; for the excellent company and letting me borrow some of their paints, and a very cool vortex mixer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/groupshot-800-e39e10edb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Everyone&apos;s final piece from the class&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/groupshot-600-e39e10edb.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/groupshot-800-e39e10edb.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/groupshot-1000-e39e10edb.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Everyone&apos;s final pieces&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps my only minor critique (and I do mean minor) would be that it would have been nice if we had a full arm with the sword on which to play around with so that we could try NMM on more shapes and surfaces. However, I very much appreciate that sourcing enough bits for us to paint is likely a pain and, since we pretty much went to time on just the sword and hand, I don’t even know if we would have had time to do more. Overall there was also a really good balance struck to allow the wide range of skill levels to get the most out of the session. I certainly learnt so much more than I was expecting and I’m looking forward to trying this out on characters and other special models in the future to build my confidence further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe there are several more classes planned on basing and faces with Mamikon so if you are interested in getting some classes with him (which I heartily recommend), feel free to message him on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/nokipaintingstudio/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MamikonPaints&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. I definitely know that now I have the itch I want to get involved in many more classes where I can over the next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for such a great day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/final_result-800-eb2db34e5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Non-metallic metal swords&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/final_result-600-eb2db34e5.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/final_result-800-eb2db34e5.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-17-niko-class/final_result-1000-eb2db34e5.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>ollie</name></author><category term="Review" /><summary type="html">I like to think (and I certainly hope you would agree) that I’m a fairly good painter, or at least I certainly know my way around a paintbrush. However, one of my main problems with improving my skills is that it’s rare that tutorials and videos that I am watching apply directly to what it is I am trying to do - be it different colours, models or just knowing when to use it. This means that if something ends up not quite how I was expecting, it can make it hard to specifically diagnose whether it’s my technique, the colours I’m using or how I’m actually applying the new skill. For years I’ve wanted to go to painting classes to try and alleviate this issue and also have the chance to talk directly to people that I know can do what I’m trying to achieve. Unfortunately, due to logistics, cost or more recently a global pandemic I’ve never had a chance - until now.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Road to Indomitus Part 1&amp;amp;#58 The Sons of Medusa</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/showcase/2021/10/11/indomitus-pt1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Road to Indomitus Part 1&amp;amp;#58 The Sons of Medusa" /><published>2021-10-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-10-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/showcase/2021/10/11/indomitus-pt1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/showcase/2021/10/11/indomitus-pt1.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/group_black-800-baaff5cb7.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/group_black-600-baaff5cb7.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/group_black-800-baaff5cb7.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/group_black-1000-baaff5cb7.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TLDR: I finally have my Space Marine chapter decided, I just need help with the greens…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I’m still here. I tried to start this site with a lot of gusto in the hope that it would give me the motivation to get projects finished and share it with you all. Alas, it has not materialised in the way I hoped, BUT I think finally I can really get started in earnest with the Space Marines I have been trying to get painted over the last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone that has been following my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/ifthehuefits.blog/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; over the last year will have seen various intermittent posts as I try every possible permutation of colours I liked under the son for my Primaris marines. Originally I wanted to do something akin to Sons of the Phoenix, but with black armour and a green arm, then I decided that I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; liked the Jade colour made by Kabalite green so wanted that to be my main colour with some other secondary arm but something still wasn’t quite clicking how I hoped. I was ideally looking for some sort of homebrew chapter that would give me enough scope for conversions, certainly not a mainstream chapter at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, quite by accident, I stumbled across Richard Walker’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CRmB3PEIJez/&quot;&gt;Sons of Medusa&lt;/a&gt; the tutorial for which can be found on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/siegestudios&quot;&gt;Siege Studio’s patreon&lt;/a&gt;. I had never come across them before so started having a look at the lore and background online. For those uninitiated, the Sons of Medusa are an Iron Hands successor chapter, specifically three of the Iron Hands clans that splintered off to form their own chapter. While most armies I see online show them as a lime green similar to Salamanders, &lt;em&gt;technically&lt;/em&gt; their armour is described as emerald in the lore, and that was absolutely the colour I wanted to do mine. So that’s it, right? I just use the jade/emerald colour I used in my original test models and move on right? WRONG! I discovered actually that Kabalite green was just that bit too dark that I didn’t think there was enough contrast between the black and the rest of the armour. The search was narrowed, but it does still continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pick-your-fighter&quot;&gt;Pick your fighter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I bit the bullet, and rather than stripping and repainting the same 5 space marines over and over, I figured I would finally just try painting a Primaris marine, three in fact! So I need input: forget what the Sons of Medusa &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; look like, and instead just tell me which green you prefer. In the image at the start of this post, from left to right we have VMC Emerald, VMC Park Green Flat and VGC Jade. I think they all have their merits, and it’s particularly hard for me to decide. I think the Emerald and Jade are very similar anyway and think that the Jade is just a bit richer, but Park Green v Jade is the toughy. That said, I am really happy with all of them, and may even go as far as to say they are some of the best minis I’ve painted - lockdown has given me a long time to watch painting videos!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some still minor details that I want to sort with the colours, in particular the colour of the chest Aquila, and I might play around with the tone of the heads a bit more. Finally, there are the transfers to add as well, along with the black knee caps, but I don’t think that will massively affect anyone’s preference so I’ve left it for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;emerald&quot;&gt;Emerald&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row; margin:0;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Emerald5-800-d8bd72ec9.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Emerald5-600-d8bd72ec9.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Emerald5-800-d8bd72ec9.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Emerald5-1000-d8bd72ec9.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Emerald1-800-356b108e9.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Emerald1-600-356b108e9.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Emerald1-800-356b108e9.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Emerald1-1000-356b108e9.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Emerald3-800-c9ec46762.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Emerald3-600-c9ec46762.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Emerald3-800-c9ec46762.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Emerald3-1000-c9ec46762.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jade&quot;&gt;Jade&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row; margin:0;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Jade1-800-00121b140.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Jade1-600-00121b140.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Jade1-800-00121b140.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Jade1-1000-00121b140.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Jade3-800-b7c3b9e77.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Jade3-600-b7c3b9e77.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Jade3-800-b7c3b9e77.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Jade3-1000-b7c3b9e77.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Jade4-800-26a350fde.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Jade4-600-26a350fde.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Jade4-800-26a350fde.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Jade4-1000-26a350fde.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;park-green-flat&quot;&gt;Park Green Flat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row; margin:0;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Park1-800-21f6abd27.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Park1-600-21f6abd27.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Park1-800-21f6abd27.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Park1-1000-21f6abd27.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Park5-800-fdcf1aee2.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Park5-600-fdcf1aee2.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Park5-800-fdcf1aee2.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Park5-1000-fdcf1aee2.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Park4-800-6de2131fa.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Park4-600-6de2131fa.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Park4-800-6de2131fa.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-10-11-indomitus-pt1/Park4-1000-6de2131fa.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also been trying to refine my miniature photography a bit too to try and improve the quality of the images. Annoyingly I haven’t been able to hit the sweet spot with the colour correction so my physical favourite (by a slim margin) is not the same as my favourite picked straight from the images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, let me know your thoughts, I’ll be putting various polls up on all the socials over the next week so tell me what you think, and hopefully, soon you’ll see a whole squad. Once I’ve settled on the scheme and got a few more done, I will eventually get round to putting a tutorial together for them too.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ollie</name></author><category term="Showcase" /><summary type="html">TLDR: I finally have my Space Marine chapter decided, I just need help with the greens… Yes, I’m still here. I tried to start this site with a lot of gusto in the hope that it would give me the motivation to get projects finished and share it with you all. Alas, it has not materialised in the way I hoped, BUT I think finally I can really get started in earnest with the Space Marines I have been trying to get painted over the last year.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Han &amp;amp; Leia</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/showcase/2021/01/05/han-leia.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Han &amp;amp; Leia" /><published>2021-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/showcase/2021/01/05/han-leia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/showcase/2021/01/05/han-leia.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/hanleia2-800-e72d764f5.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/hanleia2-600-e72d764f5.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/hanleia2-800-e72d764f5.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/hanleia2-1000-e72d764f5.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boy, it feels good to be painting again. Having not picked up a brush since moving to London in September these busts have been a real joy to paint. Sculpted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/reubenlowde/&quot;&gt;Reuben Lowde&lt;/a&gt;, these resin cast Han and Leia busts are available now on his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.etsy.com/uk/shop/ReubenLowdeArt?ref=ss_profilei&quot;&gt;Etsy store&lt;/a&gt; - Reuben very kindly sent me through a pair to paint up for him. This has been the first time I’ve painted something that isn’t a 28mm scale miniature so it’s been a real learning curve, but an incredibly useful one. What was so surprising about the jump to larger-scale was how I found the blending easier? I was expecting with more space the steps would be more obvious, but in fact, having more surface to work with made it easier to get a consistent colour gradient.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, I didn’t plan ahead and take pictures of every stage but hopefully, the descriptions below should be useful. In any case, it would be great to know your thoughts and any feedback on the formats of these articles - drop your comments below or get in touch on any of my socials!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row; margin:0;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Han1-800-e61b0ea8b.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Han1-600-e61b0ea8b.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Han1-800-e61b0ea8b.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Han1-1000-e61b0ea8b.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Han2-800-d72a7ecba.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Han2-600-d72a7ecba.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Han2-800-d72a7ecba.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Han2-1000-d72a7ecba.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row; margin:0;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Han3-800-e29b73e73.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Han3-600-e29b73e73.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Han3-800-e29b73e73.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Han3-1000-e29b73e73.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Han4-800-733d054be.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Han4-600-733d054be.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Han4-800-733d054be.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Han4-1000-733d054be.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row; margin:0;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Leia1-800-316ea401d.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Leia1-600-316ea401d.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Leia1-800-316ea401d.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Leia1-1000-316ea401d.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Leia2-800-20e538917.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Leia2-600-20e538917.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Leia2-800-20e538917.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Leia2-1000-20e538917.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row; margin:0;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Leia3-800-2495457bf.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Leia3-600-2495457bf.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Leia3-800-2495457bf.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Leia3-1000-2495457bf.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Leia4-800-3a5e85a73.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Leia4-600-3a5e85a73.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Leia4-800-3a5e85a73.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/Leia4-1000-3a5e85a73.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prep&quot;&gt;Prep&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first time I have ever tried zenithal priming, and I’m not gonna lie, once I did it I kind of wanted to just leave it as it is. There is something about all the shading that it naturally applies that I find fascinating. I don’t know if I made use of it the best I could since I largely just basecoated over the top of it, but these pictures I took before I did anything else really helped to guide me with shadow placements as I hadn’t really thought about lighting in this much detail before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;padding:0 calc(5% - 5px);&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row; max-width:500px; margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto; &quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/zenithal1-800-0d370c68c.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/zenithal1-600-0d370c68c.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/zenithal1-800-0d370c68c.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/zenithal1-1000-0d370c68c.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/zenithal2-800-b6f61e2b8.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/zenithal2-600-b6f61e2b8.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/zenithal2-800-b6f61e2b8.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/zenithal2-1000-b6f61e2b8.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;skin&quot;&gt;Skin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the paints I used for the skin were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Screamer Pink&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Doombull brown&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bugman’s Glow&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cadian Fleshtone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kislev Flesh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flayed One Flesh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ogryn Flesh wash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for Han, starting with a flat base of Bugman’s Glow, I then slowly layered up to Kislev flesh, keeping the paints really thin to glaze them over the areas I wanted to highlight. I usually created a mid-tone between each layer with a 50:50 mix of the darker or lighter paint. For areas that needed darkening down a little bit, particularly the recesses around the nose and eyes, I added in a small amount of screamer pink to the Bugman’s glow for Han, and Doombull brown for Leia. I then took some really thinned down Flayed One flesh to pick out the places the light would hit such as the side of the nose, and forehead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lips, I used a thinned down version of the shading colour and glazed that over, I was pleasantly surprised how nice the tone that produced was! Finally, to add a little bit more contrast and warmth to the cheeks, I applied a thin layer of water over the cheek area, and then just glazed some Ogryn flesh into the lower regions. The water all over helps to allow the wash to diffuse a little bit and reduce tide marks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a slightly different approach for Leia generally. I still started with Bugmans Glow and layered up to Cadian fleshtone. This time though, now I had done it once I wanted to play a bit more with directional lighting. I added a very small amount of black to the Cadian Fleshtone to de-saturate it a bit and used that in areas not directly exposed to the light. I then highlighted this area with a bit of white added to the mix. I think it worked quite well and the directional lighting is certainly visible on the model, but next time I think I could exaggerate it a little further to make it more obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;max-width:250px&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/skin-800-5d7045ce6.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/skin-600-5d7045ce6.jpg 600w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/skin-800-5d7045ce6.jpg 800w, /generated/images/2021-01-05-han-leia/skin-1000-5d7045ce6.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hair&quot;&gt;Hair&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hair was done in the same way for both busts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rhinox Hide&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mournfang Brown&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leather Brown (Vallejo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agrax Earthshade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like with the skin I worked up from darkest to lightest mixing a mid-tone between each step. Make sure to keep the paint really thin and have patience with each layer to build up the smooth gradient. While washes don’t normally work as well on large scale features, the hair still has a lot of texture, so I applied a thin all over wash to the hair, being slightly heavier towards the bottom of the hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I applied a light drybrush of Rhinox Hide to the darker areas and Leather Brown to the lighter areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hans-jacket&quot;&gt;Han’s Jacket&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am really happy with this, Corvus Black is probably my favourite colour right now. It’s just enough off-black that there is room for it to be darkened without it looking grey overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Abaddon black&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Corvus black&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eshin grey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dawnstone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adiminstratum grey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting with Corvus black base, I took a really thin Abaddon black into the areas I wanted to shade. I used this instead of a wash or contrast because you can eventually reach 100% opacity with the acrylic paint vs a wash. I also really liked the slight satin finish of Abaddon black, particularly for the leather jacket. To maximise the contrast, the darkest areas of black would be highlighted right next to it with the lighter greys, as with previous working up with mixed mid-tones and thin glazes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At about the dawnstone level, I added a couple of small scratches to the leather to give it a bit more texture and aged look. Some of these were then also highlighted with Adiminstratum grey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, to blend it all together I did a thin glaze of Abaddon black all over to tie together all the highlights a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hans-shirt&quot;&gt;Han’s Shirt&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celestra Grey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ulthuan grey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ushabti Bone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zandri Dust&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Khemri Brown (Old GW)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;White Scar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A base of Celestra grey was used to make it easier to layer up to a pure basecoat of Ulthuan grey. Then using the brown tones I shaded down to the darkest, before highlighting the edges with pure white scar to make the edges pop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since there were more purples and browns in Han’s skin tone I thought it was important to make sure the shirt had an overall warm tone to it too. As you can see I took a slightly different approach to Leia’s shirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;leias-jacket&quot;&gt;Leia’s Jacket&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zandri Dust&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ushabti Bone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Screaming Skull&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Khemri Brown (Old GW)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agrax Earthshade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working from a flat basecoat I layered up to pure Screaming Skull, carefully glazing to get the smooth transition up to the highlights. Kemri brown was then used to darken the recesses. Zandri dust and Khemri Brown are quite close so I didn’t bother with an intermediate mix. Instead, I wetted the area as I did with the skin, I then glazed the darkest recesses with Agrax Earthshade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;leias-shirt&quot;&gt;Leia’s Shirt&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thunderhawk blue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fenrisian Grey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celestra Grey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ulthuan grey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;White Scar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like with Han’s shirt, Leia’s I worked up to a pure Ulthuan Grey basecoat and then shaded down through Celestra Grey and Fenrisian Grey. A small amount of Thunderhawk blue was then shaded into the deep recesses. Finally, highlight back up to White scar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;eyes&quot;&gt;Eyes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ulthuan Grey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mournfang Brown/ Castellan Green&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leather Brown (Vallejo)/ Loren Forest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;White scar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to start with an off white for eyes as it gives room for the specular reflections to pop. I kept a thin dark pink line in the shadow between the whites and the eyelids to keep them separated. Then starting with the darkest green or brown I slowly highlighted up the iris like a gem - keeping the highlights only in the bottom corner. Finally, add the specular reflection in the opposite upper corner. For the final touch add a small amount of gloss varnish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m really proud of these models and it gave me the time to try out techniques and styles that I haven’t touched before on tabletop minis. I was able to play around with cold vs light contrasts, particularly with the shirts, as well as how to create texture on surfaces. I thought I would be painting these as a one-off, but I have to admit now I have the itch to try larger-scale pieces I would definitely be interested in getting some more busts to work with. If you like the look of these be sure to check out Reuben’s Etsy shop to get your own!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ollie</name></author><category term="Showcase" /><summary type="html">Boy, it feels good to be painting again. Having not picked up a brush since moving to London in September these busts have been a real joy to paint. Sculpted by Reuben Lowde, these resin cast Han and Leia busts are available now on his Etsy store - Reuben very kindly sent me through a pair to paint up for him. This has been the first time I’ve painted something that isn’t a 28mm scale miniature so it’s been a real learning curve, but an incredibly useful one. What was so surprising about the jump to larger-scale was how I found the blending easier? I was expecting with more space the steps would be more obvious, but in fact, having more surface to work with made it easier to get a consistent colour gradient.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Is This Thing On?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/editorial/2020/11/24/is-this-thing-on.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is This Thing On?" /><published>2020-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/editorial/2020/11/24/is-this-thing-on</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/editorial/2020/11/24/is-this-thing-on.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/generated/images/warhammer/canoptek_spyder_4-800-9b47eee6b.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/warhammer/canoptek_spyder_4-600-9b47eee6b.jpg 600w, /generated/images/warhammer/canoptek_spyder_4-800-9b47eee6b.jpg 800w, /generated/images/warhammer/canoptek_spyder_4-1000-9b47eee6b.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well hey there, thanks for dropping in, and welcome to the inaugural post on If the Hue Fits! I’m Ollie the blog’s creator and I hope this site can act as a repository not only for my own ideas and projects but hopefully as inspiration and guidance for yours. I hold no illusions of being a professional painter, but I like to think I can get together a decent enough model that it might be worth sharing with other people and talk about how I did it - in a similar vibe to the great people at &lt;a href=&quot;https://taleofpainters.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Tale of Painters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-can-i-expect&quot;&gt;What can I expect?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this blog will contain a myriad of articles that might pique your interest, including (but not limited too):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Works in Progress/ Showcases of my latest projects to help give me the motivation to reduce my pile of shame.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tutorials on certain models that you guys like, or things that I know I struggled with when I was first starting out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reviews, not necessarily on anything newly released, but on anything I may have bought without knowing much about it in the hope it may help you avoid making the same mistakes or promote great new discoveries!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Editorials, or just random articles on anything from what may be in my painting box, updates to the website or great gaming discoveries that I have found.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If those things sound up your street then stick around, follow me on the socials and I look forward to going on this journey with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S The Gallery is looking a bit empty right now, but hopefully, as I start to post more showcases and reasonable quality photography it should start to fill up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;okay-sure-but-what-sort-of-stuff-do-you-actually-do&quot;&gt;Okay sure, but what sort of stuff do you actually do?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I’ve collected Warhammer since 2005, only learnt how to play in 2011 and been much more focussed on painting since about 2015. My very first army was Chaos Space Marines, but you won’t see much of those since I very swiftly moved onto Necrons. I’m pretty happy with my Necron force but there is an itch with Indomitus to try and change the look since they are based on a scheme from the original 3rd edition codex. In terms of AoS/ Warhammer Fantasy, I have a steadily growing Tomb Kings army (can you sense a recurring theme?) which while isn’t directly gaining models, does constitute a significant part of my pile of shame. Some friends of mine a few years ago got me the Betrayal at Calth box also with the intent I do (you guessed it) Thousand Sons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also a smattering of Tau that will appear every now and then, which I have been collecting since 2015, so all in all a nice range of stuff in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-next&quot;&gt;And Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So things may be a bit quiet for now just while I work the kinks out of this website, as I very much taught myself web-dev so I could make this. Currently, with Indomitus, I am making my first foray into the Adeptus Astartes so I may be needing some help with some test themes coming up, I’m also hopefully starting work on some busts by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/reubenlowde/&quot;&gt;Reuben Lowde&lt;/a&gt; which you should definitely check out also. In the meantime, enjoy the cheeky smattering of Necrons currently scattered across here and the gallery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row-images&quot; style=&quot;flex-direction: row;&quot;&gt;






	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/warhammer/tomb_blades_6-800-7e303c051.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/warhammer/tomb_blades_6-600-7e303c051.jpg 600w, /generated/images/warhammer/tomb_blades_6-800-7e303c051.jpg 800w, /generated/images/warhammer/tomb_blades_6-1000-7e303c051.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

	
	
	
	
&lt;figure class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img style=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/generated/images/warhammer/triarch_stalker_3-800-62ef2c273.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/images/warhammer/triarch_stalker_3-600-62ef2c273.jpg 600w, /generated/images/warhammer/triarch_stalker_3-800-62ef2c273.jpg 800w, /generated/images/warhammer/triarch_stalker_3-1000-62ef2c273.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;

	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>ollie</name></author><category term="Editorial" /><summary type="html">Well hey there, thanks for dropping in, and welcome to the inaugural post on If the Hue Fits! I’m Ollie the blog’s creator and I hope this site can act as a repository not only for my own ideas and projects but hopefully as inspiration and guidance for yours. I hold no illusions of being a professional painter, but I like to think I can get together a decent enough model that it might be worth sharing with other people and talk about how I did it - in a similar vibe to the great people at Tale of Painters.</summary></entry></feed>