<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ifthehuefits.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://ifthehuefits.github.io//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-11-10T22:51:55+00:00</updated><id>https://ifthehuefits.github.io//feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Is This Thing On?</title><link href="https://ifthehuefits.github.io//editorial/2020/09/21/is-this-thing-on.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is This Thing On?" /><published>2020-09-21T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-09-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://ifthehuefits.github.io//editorial/2020/09/21/is-this-thing-on</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ifthehuefits.github.io//editorial/2020/09/21/is-this-thing-on.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Canoptek Spyder&quot; src=&quot;/generated/assets/images/warhammer/canoptek_spyder_4-800-9b47eee6b.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/assets/images/warhammer/canoptek_spyder_4-20-9b47eee6b.jpg 20w, /generated/assets/images/warhammer/canoptek_spyder_4-100-9b47eee6b.jpg 100w, /generated/assets/images/warhammer/canoptek_spyder_4-250-9b47eee6b.jpg 250w, /generated/assets/images/warhammer/canoptek_spyder_4-400-9b47eee6b.jpg 400w, /generated/assets/images/warhammer/canoptek_spyder_4-600-9b47eee6b.jpg 600w, /generated/assets/images/warhammer/canoptek_spyder_4-800-9b47eee6b.jpg 800w, /generated/assets/images/warhammer/canoptek_spyder_4-1000-9b47eee6b.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well hey there, thanks for dropping in, and welcome to the inaugural post on In the Hue Fits! I’m Ollie the blog’s creator and I hope this site can act a a repository not only for my own ideas and projects but hopefully as inspiration and guidance for yours. I hold not illusions of being a professional painter, but I like to think I can get together a decent enough model that it might be worth sharing with other people and talk about how I did it - in a similar vibe to the great people at Tale of Painters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-can-i-expect&quot;&gt;What can I expect?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this blog will contain a myriad of articles that might pique your interest, including (but not limited too):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Works in Progress/ Showcases of my latest projects to help give me the motivation to reduce my pile of shame.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tutorials on certain models that you guys like, or things that I know I struggled with when I was first starting out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reviews, not necessarily on anything newly released, but on anything I may have bought without knowing much about it in the hope it may help you avoid making the same mistakes or promote great new discoveries!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Editorials, or just random articles on anything from what may be in my painting box, updates to the webiste or great gaming discoveries that I have found.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If those things sound up your street then stick around, follow me on the socials and I look forward to going on this journey with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S The Gallery is looking a bit empty right now, but hopefully as I start to post more showcases and reasonable quality photography it should start to fill up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;okay-sure-but-what-sort-of-stuff-do-you-actually-do&quot;&gt;Okay sure, but what sort of stuff do you actually do?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well I’ve collected warhammer since 2005, only learnt how to play in 2012 and been much more focussed on painting since about 2015. My very first army was Chaos Space Marines, but you won’t see much of those since I very swiftly moved onto Necrons. I’m pretty happy with my Necron force but there is an itch with Indomitus to try and change the look since they are based on a scheme from the original 3rd edition codex. In terms of AoS/ Warhammer Fantasy I have a steadily growing Tomb Kings army (can you sense a recurring theme?) which while isn’t directly gaining models, does constitute a significant part of my pile of shame. Some friends of mine a few years ago got my the Betrayal at Calth bx also with the intent I do (you guessed it) Thousand Sons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also a smattering of Tau that will appear every now and then, which I have been collecting since 2015, so all in all a nice range of stuff in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-next&quot;&gt;And Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So things may be a bit quiet for now just while I work the kinks out of this website, as I very much taught myself web-dev so I could make this, but currently I am making my first foray into the Adeptus Astartes so I may be needing some help with some test themes coming up. In the meantime, here is a cheeky smattering of Necrons to whet your appetite.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ollie</name></author><category term="Editorial" /><summary type="html">Well hey there, thanks for dropping in, and welcome to the inaugural post on In the Hue Fits! I’m Ollie the blog’s creator and I hope this site can act a a repository not only for my own ideas and projects but hopefully as inspiration and guidance for yours. I hold not illusions of being a professional painter, but I like to think I can get together a decent enough model that it might be worth sharing with other people and talk about how I did it - in a similar vibe to the great people at Tale of Painters.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kiwi</title><link href="https://ifthehuefits.github.io//tutorials/2018/08/22/kiwi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kiwi" /><published>2018-08-22T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://ifthehuefits.github.io//tutorials/2018/08/22/kiwi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ifthehuefits.github.io//tutorials/2018/08/22/kiwi.html">&lt;p&gt;Kiwifruit (often abbreviated as kiwi), or Chinese gooseberry is the edible
berry of several species of woody vines in the genus Actinidia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common cultivar group of kiwifruit is oval, about the size of a large
hen’s egg (5–8 cm (2.0–3.1 in) in length and 4.5–5.5 cm (1.8–2.2 in) in
diameter). It has a fibrous, dull greenish-brown skin and bright green or
golden flesh with rows of tiny, black, edible seeds. The fruit has a soft
texture, with a sweet and unique flavor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/generated/assets/images/kiwi-800-c7cecf32a.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/assets/images/kiwi-20-c7cecf32a.jpg 20w, /generated/assets/images/kiwi-100-c7cecf32a.jpg 100w, /generated/assets/images/kiwi-250-c7cecf32a.jpg 250w, /generated/assets/images/kiwi-400-c7cecf32a.jpg 400w, /generated/assets/images/kiwi-600-c7cecf32a.jpg 600w, /generated/assets/images/kiwi-800-c7cecf32a.jpg 800w, /generated/assets/images/kiwi-1000-c7cecf32a.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ollie</name></author><category term="Tutorials" /><summary type="html">Kiwifruit (often abbreviated as kiwi), or Chinese gooseberry is the edible berry of several species of woody vines in the genus Actinidia. The most common cultivar group of kiwifruit is oval, about the size of a large hen’s egg (5–8 cm (2.0–3.1 in) in length and 4.5–5.5 cm (1.8–2.2 in) in diameter). It has a fibrous, dull greenish-brown skin and bright green or golden flesh with rows of tiny, black, edible seeds. The fruit has a soft texture, with a sweet and unique flavor.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bananas</title><link href="https://ifthehuefits.github.io//showcase/2018/08/02/bananas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bananas" /><published>2018-08-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://ifthehuefits.github.io//showcase/2018/08/02/bananas</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ifthehuefits.github.io//showcase/2018/08/02/bananas.html">&lt;p&gt;A banana is an edible fruit – botanically a berry – produced by several kinds
of large herbaceous flowering plants in the genus Musa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some countries, bananas used for cooking may be called “plantains”,
distinguishing them from dessert bananas. The fruit is variable in size, color,
and firmness, but is usually elongated and curved, with soft flesh rich in
starch covered with a rind, which may be green, yellow, red, purple, or brown
when ripe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;img alt=&quot;bananas&quot; src=&quot;/generated/assets/images/bananas-800-2d578396d.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/assets/images/bananas-20-2d578396d.jpg 20w, /generated/assets/images/bananas-100-2d578396d.jpg 100w, /generated/assets/images/bananas-250-2d578396d.jpg 250w, /generated/assets/images/bananas-400-2d578396d.jpg 400w, /generated/assets/images/bananas-600-2d578396d.jpg 600w, /generated/assets/images/bananas-800-2d578396d.jpg 800w, /generated/assets/images/bananas-1000-2d578396d.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
{:class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/generated/assets/images/bananas-800-2d578396d.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/assets/images/bananas-20-2d578396d.jpg 20w, /generated/assets/images/bananas-100-2d578396d.jpg 100w, /generated/assets/images/bananas-250-2d578396d.jpg 250w, /generated/assets/images/bananas-400-2d578396d.jpg 400w, /generated/assets/images/bananas-600-2d578396d.jpg 600w, /generated/assets/images/bananas-800-2d578396d.jpg 800w, /generated/assets/images/bananas-1000-2d578396d.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ollie</name></author><category term="Showcase" /><summary type="html">A banana is an edible fruit – botanically a berry – produced by several kinds of large herbaceous flowering plants in the genus Musa. In some countries, bananas used for cooking may be called “plantains”, distinguishing them from dessert bananas. The fruit is variable in size, color, and firmness, but is usually elongated and curved, with soft flesh rich in starch covered with a rind, which may be green, yellow, red, purple, or brown when ripe.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Apples</title><link href="https://ifthehuefits.github.io//review/2018/02/21/apples.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apples" /><published>2018-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ifthehuefits.github.io//review/2018/02/21/apples</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ifthehuefits.github.io//review/2018/02/21/apples.html">&lt;p&gt;An apple is a sweet, edible fruit produced by an apple tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple trees are cultivated worldwide, and are the most widely grown species in
the genus Malus. The tree originated in Central Asia, where its wild ancestor,
Malus sieversii, is still found today. Apples have been grown for thousands of
years in Asia and Europe, and were brought to North America by European
colonists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/generated/assets/images/apples-732-370706f53.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/generated/assets/images/apples-20-370706f53.jpg 20w, /generated/assets/images/apples-250-370706f53.jpg 250w, /generated/assets/images/apples-400-370706f53.jpg 400w, /generated/assets/images/apples-600-370706f53.jpg 600w, /generated/assets/images/apples-732-370706f53.jpg 732w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ollie</name></author><category term="Review" /><summary type="html">An apple is a sweet, edible fruit produced by an apple tree. Apple trees are cultivated worldwide, and are the most widely grown species in the genus Malus. The tree originated in Central Asia, where its wild ancestor, Malus sieversii, is still found today. Apples have been grown for thousands of years in Asia and Europe, and were brought to North America by European colonists.</summary></entry></feed>